本字幕由好字幕网www.haosub.com中文站搜集
翻译by @Ash十架 /微博 野生字幕 才疏学浅 欢迎捉虫 谢谢支持
我不知道如何 讲述这个故事
I have no idea how to tell this story.
我甚至不知道 从哪里开始讲起
I don't even know how to start it.
比如 我可以用那种 牛逼作家讲故事的
Like, I guess I could use one of those classic
经典开头
story beginning sentences.
"这是最好的时代 这是最坏的时代"
"It was the best of times; it was the worst of times."
但这又有什么意义呢？
But what would that even mean?
我是说 可能在世界上的某个地方
I mean, obviously, somewhere in the world,
对于某人来说 这是最好的时代
it's the best of times for someone.
比如 他狼吞虎咽
Like he's eating all this insane
他免费得到的越南菜
Vietnamese food he just got for free...
然后 给他送餐的女士
...and the woman who delivered the food
热辣得就像 造反猫咪乐队里那些尤物一样
looks exactly like the hot girl from Pussy Riot
而此刻 她正坐在角落
and now she's situated in the corner
在竖琴上 弹奏着 难以言说的美妙旋律
playing unspeakably beautiful melodies on the harp.
他就伴着这样的美妙音乐吃吃吃
While he's just going to town on that food.
这么说的话 他确实在“最好的时代”
So, yeah, that's the best of times.
但与此同时 在世界另一个角落 另一个人
Meanwhile, some other guy is having
他的意志 被欺凌专业户折磨
his will broken by professional torturers...
被扔进一个 满是鳄鱼的酸性池
over a crocodile-infested pool of acid.
正因为是酸性池
And because it's acid,
所以鳄鱼们都脾气不小
these crocodiles are just pissed.
他们还从通风管道里 排入那种
And they're also piping in that gross smell you get...
在学校停车场泼牛奶时
...when they spill a bunch of milk
的那种臭气
in the school parking lot.
然后四肢发达的欺凌专业户
And this beefy torture dude
把他的翔都打出来了
is just punching the hell out of him.
这 绝对是“最坏的时代”
Check.
我不知道我在什么
好吧 好吧 我还是讲我的故事吧
All right, look. I'll just start.
这个故事讲的是我的高三
This is the story of my senior year of high school
以及这段日子是如何毁了我的生活
and how it destroyed my life.
又及我是拍了怎么样烂的一部电影 烂到真的“烂死”了一个人
And how I made a film so bad, it literally killed someone.
片名：我 和 厄 尔 以 及 将
死 的 女 孩 中字by @Ash十架 /微博
我是这么开始高三生活的
我曾经这么觉得：
I used to think about it this way:
Schenley高中 是一个自己的小小世界
Schenley High School was a world unto itself.
上到高三 我已经颇为牛逼地掌握了
By senior year, I had mastered the languages and customs
每一个小团体的 风俗和语言
of its various sovereign states.
体育生打招呼的方式是点头
The head nods of Jock Nation.
吸大麻的团体 习惯击拳
The fist bumps of the Kingdom of Stoners.
戏剧社的白痴们
The innocuous witticisms of
喜欢说 无伤大雅的俏皮话
The People's Republic of Theater Dorks.
Greg 你暑假过得如何？
Greg, how was your summer?
暑假（Summer）？我都不知道这词啥意思
Summer. What does that word even mean?
是"summ"的比较级吗？
Like, more "summ"?
在传统的高中生活中
In a typical high school life,
我们都要挑选一个属于自己的团体
you belong to one nation...
但这样 也不能保证你100%的安全感
...which can never guarantee you total security.
不过 我想了个好主意
But I thought I found a way out.
在每个团体 都成为合法公民
Get citizenship in every nation.
在每个团体 都可互通有无
Get passports to everywhere.
低调地与每个人都成为好友
Just be on low-key good terms with everyone...
时不时跟他们交流一下
...casually interact with them once in a while...
只要别让其他团体发现就好
...in a way that is invisible to everyone else.
拒绝一切不是非正式的
Never commit to an interaction
以及非暴力的交流
that won't be casual or mellow.
你的小考是在今天吗？
Your test was today?
天啦噜 小考！我懂你
Ugh. Tests! I've been there.
就好像是往阿富汗输送士兵
That's like sending troops to Afghanistan.
让他们与世界上最暴乱的国家的公民
Maintain relationships with citizens
保持一种关系
of the most dicked-upon nations.
比如说 Scott Mayhew
For example, Scott Mayhew,
我身边坐着的这位 哥特狂魔
the gothy dork I'm sitting next to here.
Scott 你这狂暴战士不错啊
Scott, nice Berserker.
...谢了?
Thank you?
我花费了几年的时间用心栽培 才赢得他的信任
It took years of cultivation to win his trust.
或者是随大流地一起抵制Ill Phil
Or the universally ostracized Ill Phil.
这就是传说中的大一统
Truly a nation of one.
当然 也有一些地方 我是绝对不能去的
And there were some places I simply couldn't go.
比如食堂
Like the cafeteria.
在那里 每个角落 都充满着恐怖主义
Every last square inch of it was disputed territory.
就像是克里米亚 克什米尔
It was Crimea, Kashmir,
还有加沙地带的结合体
and the Gaza Strip all rolled into one.
可能还包括着 印度洋上的海盗
Also the part of the Indian Ocean with pirates.
是《菲利普船长》里那种 海盗 不是 《加勒比海盗》那种
Captain Phillips pirates, not Pirates of the Caribbean.
不过 谁知道呢 或许两种都有
Although, actually, who knows? Maybe both.
“梦想的负担” 所以 我都在老师办公室里吃午饭
Instead, I always ate lunch in the office
他是我们的历史老师
of my history teacher.
McCarthy先生
Mr. McCarthy.
事实:
Fact:
我要在309待...20分钟
I'm in 309 for the next... 20 minutes.
他是Schenley高中 唯一一个正常的成年人
The only reasonable adult in all of Schenley.
小鬼们
Heathens.
尊重研究！
Respect the research.
我一般跟Earl在一起 他在我人生中扮演的角色
With Earl, whose role in my life
我现在不准备给你们解释
I'm not even gonna try to explain to you right now.
屏幕上播放赫尔佐格的《路上行舟》 的幕后特辑
The harmony of overwhelming and collective murder.
最后还有 火辣的校花美女们 她们真的是祸水啊
Hot girls destroy your life.
这就是铁一般的事实 不管这美女是不是个好人
It doesn't matter if the hot girl is also a good person.
她是这头麋鹿 而你就是这只花栗鼠
She's a moose, you're a chipmunk.
那啥 她只是在树林里遛个弯
She's just wandering through the forest, oblivious.
根本就不会注意到 她其实踩得你脑浆迸裂
And she doesn't even know that she stomped on your head.
嗨 Madison
Hey, Madison.
嘿 你暑假过得怎么样
Hey, how was your summer?
暑假 这词到底什么意思啊
Summer. What does that word even mean, right?
"summ"的比较级
More "summ."
那寒假（Winter）也是一样咯 "wint"的比较级
Winter, same deal. More "wint"?
McCarthy先生在309教室
McCarthy's in 309.
很好 谢谢
Great, thanks.
在这一切势不可挡的痛苦
To become humbled
和势不可挡的荒唐
in front of this overwhelming misery...
以及势不可挡的混乱面前...
...and overwhelming fornication
保持低调谦恭
and overwhelming lack of order.
女人啊
Titties.
亲爱的 我们能进来吗？ 天啊 天啊
Honey, can we come in? Jesus, Jesus!
好啊 什么事？
Yeah. What do you want?
首先 我偷看了你的东西
First of all, I was going through...
然后我看到...
...your stuff and I saw that you
你的大学词典还没拆包呢
have not even unwrapped your college directory.
妈 别偷看我东西 行吗
Mom, don't go through my stuff.
我们讨论过了 所以她才去偷看你的东西
We discussed it, and she gets to go through your stuff.
你来看一下嘛 很好玩的
Just have a look. It's fun.
就像是写满你未来的菜单
It's like a menu for your future.
你想来点儿什么？宾州大学？
What are you in the mood for? Some Penn State?
佩珀代因？波莫纳？普林斯顿？
Some Pepperdine? Pomona? Princeton?
我才不会去上普林斯顿
I'm not getting into Princeton.
他不上普林斯顿
He's not getting into Princeton.
呃 那就这样吧
Um, so, is that it?
不 亲爱的 我们还没说完
No, honey, it's not it.
我和你爸想跟你谈一些挺难过的事
Your father and I want to talk to you about something kind of sad.
啥事？
What?
怎么了？
What happened?
是这样 我刚和Denise Kushner通完电话
Well, I just got off the phone with Denise Kushner,
她是Rachel的妈妈 你认识她吧？
Rachel's mom. You know Denise?
呃 不认识
Um, not really.
那你是Rachel的朋友吧
You're friends with Rachel, though.
是 我们认识而已
Yeah, I mean, we're like, acquainted.
来
Come here.
好
Okay.
Rachel刚被确诊 得了白血病
Rachel's been diagnosed with leukemia.
他们刚刚查出的
They just found out.
你的[检查]是在今天吗？
Your test was today?
天啦噜 我懂你
Ugh. Tests! I've been there.
我的天啊
Oh, God.
很严重吗？
Is that serious?
他们现在正在做各种检查
They're doing all kinds of tests.
力所能及地帮助她
They're doing everything they can.
不过他们也不知道
They just don't know.
天 这太烂了
Man, that sucks.
你说的没错
You're right.
太烂了
It sucks.
烂到不行了
It sucks really bad.
真是一件大烂事
It sucks quite a bit.
是
Yeah.
爸 史蒂猫挠我诶 （Cat Stevens是英国知名民谣歌手 恰巧名字中有一个"猫"字)
Dad, Cat Stevens is clawing me.
他也在心烦意乱呢
Well, he's deeply distraught.
是这样 我跟Denise聊了一下
Well, you know, I was talking to Denise...
Denise觉得 你可能
...and Denise feels that you might be someone...
能让Rachel感觉好些
...who could make Rachel feel better.
但是 我都说了
Yeah, but like I said,
我们俩真的不算是朋友
we're not really friends, so...
你可以给Rachel打个电话
Just give Rachel a call.
好啊 那你想让我说点啥呢？
Yeah, well, what do you want me to say?
就说 "嘿 我是Greg 就是那个
"Hey, it's Greg, the guy who's
"之前从没注意过你的男孩子
"never really paid attention to you...
"...但是现在你得癌症了 所以我们一起玩吧"吗？?
"...but now you have cancer, so let's hang out"?
不行 不能这么说
That's not gonna work.
她会觉得你在讽刺她的
She'll think you're being sarcastic.
你是想告诉我 你从来不会
Are you telling me you can't do
为其他人做一件好事吗？
one nice thing for another person?
你认真的吗？你真是这个意思吗？
I mean, honestly, is that really what's happening here?
好吧
Fine. Okay.
只是 真的 请别再偷看我的东西了
Just, please don't go through my stuff.
不然我就去偷看你的了
Or I'll start going through your stuff.
看吧 反正都是卫生棉条
I hope you like tampons.
It's
Central Pittsburgh on 90.5...
我是Rachel
This is Rachel.
嗨 我是Greg Gaines.
Hey, it's Greg Gaines.
嗨
Hi.
那啥 我刚刚咨询了一个医生
Yo!
So, I called a doctor...
他说你需要一种叫Greg的特效药
...he said you needed a prescription of Greg-acil.
那是什么？
What's that?
呃...
Uh...
就是我啦
It's me.
胶囊包装 方便冲服哦
In convenient gel-tab form.
哦
Oh.
是啊
Yeah.
我猜你已经听说 我病了
So, I guess you heard I'm sick.
是
Yeah.
是我妈跟你说的吗？
Did my mom tell you?
呃 是我妈跟我说的
Um, well, my mom told me.
哦
Oh.
那啥...
So, um...
什么？
What?
什么什么？
你要说什么？
What were you gonna say?
呃...
Um...
Greg 你到底要说什么
Greg, what?
呃 我只是打电话来问问你
Uh, yeah, I was just calling to see
要不要跟我一起玩
if you wanted to hang out.
现在？
Right now?
是啊
Um, sure.
不要了 谢了
No, thanks.
哦
Oh.
那你是不想和我玩咯
Okay, so you don't wanna hang out?
不想 不过还是谢谢你
No. Thanks anyways.
好吧 那啥 再见
Okay. Um, bye.
拜拜
Bye.
妈 你又在干啥啊
Mom, what are you doing?
听着 妈 她不想见我
Okay, Mom, listen, she doesn't want to see me.
我真的不想这么说 Gregory
I'm sorry to be the one to tell you, Gregory...
但是在这样的情况下
...that you do not have a choice
我们通常是没有选择的
in this particular matter.
妈 让我说一句话 好么
Mom, please, let me say one thing for one second.
这是你的大好机会
You have been given an opportunity
可以给他人的生命 带去不一样的改变
to make a very real difference in someone's life.
但如果你选择了
And if what you're choosing instead
每天在家里挺尸
is to lie around the house all day...
她又不想见我！
She doesn't want to see me!
那我就要好好管管你了
...I will be required to step in...
我们连朋友都不是！
We're not even friends!
跟你说 你这样的行为 不可接受
...and inform you that that is 100% unacceptable.
你唠唠叨叨的快把我逼疯了！
Your nonstop stream of words is making me freak out!
如果你觉得你的这些借口
And if you think that all these excuses you're making
比一个患癌的女孩的快乐
are in any way better...
更有趣...
...or more important, than the happiness
或者更重要的话
of a girl with cancer...
妈 你搞得我里外不是人啊
Mom! I am now entering a subhuman state.
患癌的是你的朋友啊
...a friend with cancer,
你犯下了一个可悲的错误 小朋友
you are sadly mistaken, my friend.
你现在就拿起电话来
You are going to pick up that phone.
再给Rachel打个电话
You're going to call Rachel again.
现在就打 现在就打
You are going to. You are going to.
我是这么和将死的女孩见面的
哦 Greg.
Oh, Greg.
哦 Kushner夫人
Oh, Mrs. Kushner.
Greg 叫我Denise
Denise, Greg.
对你来说 我是Denise 好吗
To you, I'm Denise, okay?
好吧 好的
Oh, okay. Good.
你知道吗 你是个很好的孩子
You're a real good kid, you know that?
真的 你心地真的很善良
You really are. You just have a big heart.
你又善良又体贴
You're kind, nice.
真的很谢谢你
I really appreciate it.
谢谢
Thank you.
特别特别特别特别特别
Good, good, good, good, good...
好的一个男孩子
...good boy.
好吧
Okay.
你是个善良 体贴 可口
You really are kind, big-hearted, delicious...
...特别特别特别可口的小男孩
...yummy, yummy, young boy.
你真的帅呆了
And you're so, so, handsome.
我一点都不帅 不过谢谢你
Oh, I'm not handsome, but thank you.
还这么谦虚
And so modest.
是 我就是谦逊得跟耗子似的
I guess I'm a modest mouse.
Greg 你是怎么想出这个说法来的？
Greg, where do you come up with this stuff?
哦 只是引用一个乐队名字
Well, that's the name of a band, actually.
哦 是
Oh. Yeah.
Rachel!
一只谦逊的小耗子来看你了
I've got a modest little mouse here to see you!
Rachel
Rachel.
Greg 你来干嘛？
Greg, what are you doing here?
呃...
So, uh...
...上次给你说的那个医生
...the doctor really recommends
他真的强烈推荐Greg这个药给你
a strong dosage of Gregitor.
这笑话你上次讲过了
You already used that joke.
没有
No.
上次我说的是另外一种Greg药
No, 'cause last time it was about Greg-acil...
你还记得吗 上次是一种胶囊
...which if you recall comes in convenient gel-tab form.
这样 我不想让你和我一起玩
Look, I don't want you hanging out with me.
我不想要你愚蠢的怜悯
I don't need your stupid pity.
没关系 你可以走
It's fine, you can just go.
不 不
No, no.
你错了 我不是怜悯你
You got it all wrong. I'm not here 'cause I pity you.
我来这 只是因为我妈妈逼我来
I'm actually here because my mom is making me.
还不如怜悯呢
That's actually worse.
是 我知道
Yeah, I know.
没关系的 真的 我没事 你走吧
Look, it's okay. Honestly, I'm fine. Just... just go.
好吧 Rachel 你听我说
Okay, Rachel, just listen to me for a second.
如果我不跟你玩的话
My mom is gonna turn my life into a living hell...
我妈妈就会把我的人生变成活地狱
...if I don't hang out with you.
你知道她为了这事儿唠叨得我多烦吗 我都没法儿跟你说
I can't overstate how annoying she's being about this.
他简直就是唠叨界的勒布朗·詹姆斯
She's basically like the LeBron James of nagging.
就打篮球那个
LeBron James plays basketball.
我知道勒布朗·詹姆斯
I know who LeBron James is.
我知道我并没帮上你什么忙
Look, I know I'm not doing you any favors here.
但是 我是真心求你帮我一个忙
What I'm asking is for you to do me a favor.
你 让我 帮你忙？
You want a favor from me?
是的
Yes.
就让我和你一起 玩一天
Just let me hang out with you for one day.
我就可以跟我妈说 我们确实一起玩了
I could tell my mom we hung out
然后我们就可以各走各的路了
and then we'll just be out of each other's lives.
说定了？
Deal?
说定了
Deal.
保证
Word.
你是在做黑魔法手势吗？
Is that a Black Power salute?
不是 我想击拳来着
No, I was going in for a fist bump.
我离你这么远 怎么击拳啊
I can't fist bump you from up here.
是 我才想到
Yeah, I realize that.
好多书哦
Books.
不错
Nice.
还有...
And, uh...
...树图案墙纸
...tree wallpaper.
挺好
That's good.
为啥？
Why?
我也不知道
I don't know.
失败的友谊：第一天
这里好多枕头哦
There's a lot of pillows in here.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
真心的 你有多少个枕头啊
Seriously, like, how many... how many pillows is that?
我也不知道
I don't know.
要是我有这么多枕头就好了
I wish I had that many pillows.
跟你爸妈要啊
So, ask your parents for some.
不 他们会起疑心的
No, they'd be suspicious or something.
什么疑心 会怕你睡成一头死猪吗？
What, that you'd sleep all the time?
不是 大概会怕我
No. Probably assume
撸得枕头上到处都是
I was gonna masturbate all over them.
他们总是把我想得很恶心
They just have some gross ideas about me.
不过不是我的原因啦
But that's on them.
他们总买那种性感的枕头
They're always getting sexy pillows.
这个枕头真舒服
This is a nice pillow.
这个枕头很明显是个男的
This pillow is a dude, obviously...
...不过它倒是令我想起
...but it reminds me of this pillow
我家一个叫做Francesca的枕头
we used to have named Francesca.
它们颜色差不多
They have a similar coloring.
不过最后Francesca被送人了
Anyway, Francesca, we had to eventually
因为我们俩之间...
give away because in the end...
真的挺成问题
...that whole situation was just a real problem.
真是一团糟
It was a mess.
我们之间有一种
There was a real chemistry
毋庸置疑的化学反应
between us both that I think no one could deny.
我明白 世俗并不能接受我们
I know the world may have thought it was wrong...
但是我个人觉得 世俗才是错误的
...but I think, personally, the world was wrong...
一个枕头 是可以和
...about what could be between...
一个男孩
...a pillow, and a boy...
...不是 是男人 有化学反应的
...who became a man.
爱啥啥吧 我只是
Or whatever. I'm just...
想说点搞笑的
...trying to be funny.
没有啊 你说的很好笑 谢谢
No, that was good. Thank you.
该死
Oh, shit.
你个傻逼死哪去了 我把你那份鱿鱼也吃噜* 我真得走了
I actually have to go.
没事 谁给你打电话啊？
That's okay. Who was that?
对不起 呃 是Earl
Sorry. Uh, that was Earl.
谁是Earl?
Oh, who's Earl?
你可能还记得 15分钟前我提到过Earl
You may remember Earl from 15 minutes ago.
女人啊
Titties.
是这样 大家都认为 Earl是我的朋友
So, some people think Earl is my friend,
但其实他不是的
but he's really not.
他更像是我的同事
He's more like a coworker.
打幼儿园起我就认识他
I've known him since kindergarten.
他家和我家离得很近
His house is a short walk from mine,
但是他家邻居更可怕些
but in a much tougher neighborhood.
他爸在得州 妈是个抑郁症 天天窝在家里
His dad is in Texas, his mom is a depressed shut-in.
他哥Derrick有条狗Doopie
And his brother Derrick's dog Doopie
总有一天我得 让狗活吃了
will definitely eat me someday.
Doopie 冷静！
Doopie, Doopie, chill!
所以这么些年来 我们都在我家玩
So over the years we've mostly hung out at my place.
一般都是跟我爸一起 他是终身社会学教授
Usually with my dad, a tenured sociology professor.
你多厉害啊 猫子 想打架吗？
What you got, cat? You wanna fight?
猜你也不敢吧 傻逼猫
Didn't think so, punk-ass cat.
- 孩子们 -  他的工作特性使得他
- Boys! - His job allows him
可以一直宅家 啥也不干
to be frequently at home doing nothing.
你们一定会对这个感兴趣
You'll want to pay close attention to this.
疯狂的征服者阿基尔
The insane conquistador, Aguirre,
正满腔怒火地穿过丛林
is raging through the jungle...
寻找并不存在的黄金城
...in search of a golden city that doesn't exist.
《阿基尔 上帝的愤怒》
The wrath of God.
外语片经典啊
It's a classic of foreign cinema.
谁跟我一起去？
Who else is with me?
除了最经典的佳片之外
In addition to the best films...
这是乌贼
This is cuttlefish.
我家还有最奇怪的食物
...my house also has the weirdest food.
是一种很像鱿鱼的海洋生物
A sea creature much like a squid.
这是东亚地区最受欢迎的小吃
It is a favorite East Asian snack food.
很显然 我们的生活背景不尽相同
Obviously we come from pretty different backgrounds.
但不知怎的 我们的爱好却很相似
But somehow, we like most of the same things.
好吧 但是对于我们西方人来说
Yes, its smell is odd and repellent
闻起来又怪又恶心
to our Western noses.
而且 我们很早就意识到
And we learned pretty early on
我俩是唯一喜欢...
that we were the only ones who liked...
经典外语片的
...for example, classics of foreign cinema.
我们为什么喜欢？
Why did we like them?
这很难说
It's hard to say.
可能是因为它们怪怪的 而且通常很暴力
Maybe it's that they were weird and often violent,
就像我们一样
like us.
或者有时很难理解 或者毫无意义 就像生活
Or confusing and possibly meaningless, like life.
你逃不出这个 臭烘烘的营地
You can't escape of this stinkin' camp
因为这里屁也没有 电话都接不到
because you never know when they call you.
因为你拿了钱了 你签了合同了
Because you're paid for, you're under contract.
反正吧 我们对外语片的爱过于疯狂
Anyway, we liked them so much
所以也开始拍自己的小电影了
we started making our own.
Greg和Earl制片 开拍！
Action!
每个小电影的概念都是
The idea behind each one was...
我们选一部我们喜欢的电影
...we took a film that we liked
把标题改得更蠢一点
and made the title stupider.
（恶搞电影标题《老年凯恩》《大开屁戒》 《罗丝玛丽的萝卜》《四百兄》《诺斯鼻拉图2》） 再拍成一部新的电影
And then made a new film
（恶搞电影标题《老年凯恩》《大开屁戒》 《罗丝玛丽的萝卜》《四百兄》《诺斯鼻拉图2》） 来讲述这更蠢的题目
to reflect the new stupid title.
（《吃货八部半》《狗屎男》《疯狂之鞋》 《剖析汉堡》《迷路记》很多谐音和文字游戏大家自己理解下） 这种拍电影的方式 简直就是烂片制造机
It's a formula that only produces horrible films...
（《吃货八部半》《狗屎男》《疯狂之鞋》 《剖析汉堡》《迷路记》很多谐音和文字游戏大家自己理解下） 但不知为何 我们却一直保持这个传统
...but for some reason we keep using it.
《与巨人安德烈的晚餐》
《毫无诱惑》（她是塑料人）
《精疲力尽之哮喘》
《多毛老年现代三镖客》
《威尼斯疑魂之有个小丑要杀了你 靠》
《第七海豹印》
《拉屎狂》
《疯狂荒岛惊魂》 “影评人：比《穷街陋巷》还要出色！”
《网球之死》
我们拍了42部电影
We've made 42 films.
你可能觉得 我们是时候停止毁片了
You'd think we'd have stopped making them by now.
但我们没有
But we haven't.
《尖叫的负担》图注：*大船* *疯子演员* *导演* 其实 事实是 我们也不知道我们还能干什么
Honestly, it's like you can't go anywhere.
《尖叫的负担》图注：*大船* *疯子演员* *导演* 你不可能从这 他妈的臭烘烘的地方逃离的
You can't escape this stinking place...
因为这儿屁都没有 打个电话都接不到
...because you don't know when they call you...
你是拿了钱签了合同的 简直他妈狗屁
and you're paid to be here, it's bullshit.
就这事 就这样
Yeah, and it's like, you know,
我啥都不能干 好像被囚禁
I can't do anything. I'm not a free person.
讲真 你们的作品中 我最喜欢这部
Truly, one of my favorites from your oeuvre.
对于自然暴力的探讨的成熟视角
A mature investigation into the nature of violence.
爸 我都说了130亿遍了
Dad, for like the billionth time,
你不许看我们的小电影
you're not allowed to watch these.
我是粉丝啊
I'm a fan.
你还去见那个姑娘吗？
You gonna go see that girl again?
呃 可能吧
I mean, probably, yeah.
你跟她玩爱爱么？
You gonna play with them titties?
不 我们不是那个关系
No. It's not like that.
啊 那怎么行
Well, that's not right.
我是说 这可能是这姑娘一生中
I mean, this could be her last chance on Earth
最后一次和男人共处的机会
to be with a man.
别只想着自己
Don't make this about you.
Earl!
首先 那么高风险
First of all, if it's that high-stakes,
我连勃起都不可能
probably won't even be able to get a boner.
我没说勃起吧？
Did I even say shit about boners?
没
No.
话说回来 这急性髓细胞性白血病 到底是什么癌症啊
What kind of cancer even is acute myelogenous leukemia?
呃 就是...
You know, cancer of the, uh...
...就是癌症嘛
...the thing.
全是狗屁！
It's bullshit!
安提塔姆会战是美国历史上
The Battle of Antietam was the bloodiest day
最血腥的一天
in American history.
同学们 你们有什么要说的？
Class, what do you have to say for yourselves?
尊重研究
Respect the research.
这才对嘛！
That is what I'm talking about!
好吧 逃命吧 快逃吧
All right, run for your lives.
保命重要 走吧走吧
Save yourselves. Go, go, go, go, go.
今天大家都干得不错
Good work today, everybody.
加油 做得很好
Way to go. Bam. Love it. Good stuff.
干得好 棒极了
Good job. Excellent work today.
棒极了 嘿 能跟你谈谈吗？
Excellent. Nice job. Hey, can I talk to you?
就一会儿 可以吗?
Can I talk to you for a second?
可以啊 Greg 怎么了？
Sure, Greg, what's up?
你了解白血病吗？
Uh, do you know any facts about leukemia?
白血病？
Leukemia?
哦 是一种血液和骨髓的癌症
Yeah, it's a cancer of the blood and/or bone marrow.
为什么想知道？
Why?
所以这种病症会蔓延全身？
Right, so it's pretty spread out in the body?
是的 这是个事实
That is a fact, yes.
一般得了这病 多久会死？
How soon do people die from it?
我认为这病是可治疗的
I think it's often pretty treatable, bud.
为什么问我这个？
Why do you ask?
呃 你知道Rachel Kushner 得了白血病是吧？
Well, you know Rachel Kushner has leukemia, right?
等等 Rachel怎么了？
Wait, Rachel has what?
我真的是蠢出新高度了
I'm, like, innovatively stupid.
反正大家早晚都会知道的
Everyone was gonna find out sooner or later.
我只是讨厌把自己的事情跟大家分享
Just hate having to share everything about myself.
我也是 完全一样的想法
I'm the exact same way.
你知道吗 如果你不想跟任何人说话
You know, one thing you can do
那你可以
if you don't want to talk to anyone...
进入一种非人的状态
...is just enter a subhuman state.
就这样 你先假装是一个特别烦的人
Here, pretend you're someone annoying.
"嗨 Rachel
"Hi, Rachel.
"真抱歉你得癌症了"
"I'm really sorry you have cancer."
真的有用吗？
Does that ever work?
真的 超级管用
Yeah, of course. It works all the time.
这叫做 消极抵抗
It's called passive resistance.
就是甘地搞运动的时候那一套
You know, that's what Gandhi was all about.
我并不觉得甘地这样过
I'm pretty sure Gandhi never did the subhuman thing.
印度就是这样独立的 来嘛 试一下
That's how India achieved statehood. Here, try it.
不要
Nope.
来嘛 很简单的
Come on, it's easy.
好吧 还有一种方法
Okay. Or another thing you can do is just
挺尸 装死
flat-out pretend to be dead.
快 说点什么烦我的事
Say something annoying to me.
Um...
"嗨 Rachel 我只希望你明白
"Hey, Rachel. I just want you to remember
"癌症也是上帝对你的安排"
"that your cancer is all part of God's plan."
你个混蛋
Hey, asshole.
过来
Yeah, over here.
我们说清楚
Just so we're straight on this,
你在建议一个患癌少女
you're advising a girl with cancer...
装 死
...to pretend to be dead.
说真的
No, seriously.
你个混球 用用脑子
Think about what you're doing here, dickhead.
我在这个少女的墙壁上 摆一张
I've been doing my broody Wolverine face on
金刚狼脸
this girl's wall...
已经有五又四分之一年了
...for five and a quarter years,
此时 我还被挂着的原因...
and at this point, I'm probably only still here...
可能是如果把我摘下来的话
...because she'd feel weirdly guilty
她会感到罪恶和不忠
or disloyal taking me down.
但是如果我让一个像你这样的傻瓜
But I'm goddamned if I'm letting
走进来 说些奇奇怪怪的蠢话
a little punk like you waltz in here...
我就跳墙谢罪！
...stupiding up the place!
至少我在这儿时不行
Not on my watch, pal.
Greg 你怎么了？
Greg, what's wrong?
我真心道歉
I'm really sorry.
我不应该让你装死
I shouldn't have told you to pretend to be dead.
我说话太不小心了
That was really insensitive.
但是 我只是生病啊 又不是要死了
I mean, I'm sick. I'm not dying.
是的 我懂 我只是...
Yeah, I know, but I just...
觉得这样怪怪的
Now I'm being all weird about it.
而且我没法觉得这样正常 因为
And I can't get un-weird, 'cause I just...
虽然你那么说了
Despite what you said,
但是我坐在这儿脑子里想的
I'm clearly still sitting here thinking...
全是"死亡 死亡 死亡 死亡 死亡"
..."death, death, death, death, death, death."
对对对！就这样！
That's exactly what I'm talking about!
就这样 如果这是个浪漫的琼瑶故事的话
So if this was a touching romantic story...
现在我就会
...this is probably where a new feeling
感觉被一种焕然一新的情感包围
would wash over me...
我们目光相遇 开始疯狂亲热
and suddenly we would be furiously making out...
干柴烈火 星月同辉
...with the fire of a thousand suns.
但这不是个浪漫的琼瑶故事
But this isn't a touching romantic story.
爱谁谁吧 是
Anyway... Yep.
但我们确实成为了朋友
But we did still become friends.
我和Rachel是这么变成朋友的 别名：没有回头路
失败的友谊：第四天 Daniel Craig的问题是 他口音太重了
Daniel Craig's thing is, he's got an accent, right?
所以他说话时 嘴型很奇怪
So he's used to talking with his mouth in a weird shape...
噘着嘴 像个女的
...which is why he has pouty lips, like a woman.
失败的友谊：第七日 希望有人可以发明舔屏功能 这样我就可以给你发张三明治图片 你就可以吃了
Lickable technology, like, I could text you a sandwich.
希望这是手机未来的发展方向 - 在皮肤下面 他的后脖颈上有个按钮
There's a button on the nape of his neck, under the skin.
按一下 他就停了
Just push it if you want him to stop.
失败的友谊：第八天 你相信吗 在我们家 动物和人一起住在家里
Do you believe animals just live in our house,
而且大家都觉得没什么?
and everyone's cool with it?
是活的动物哦
Like, real animals?
爱谁谁吧 该你说了
Anyway. You talk now.
你是说 让我说癌症吗？
You mean, talk about cancer?
你想的话 可以啊
Only if you want to.
我最难受的大概就是看我妈妈
The hardest part is watching my mom
试图承受这一切
trying to deal with it all.
而且有的时候我真的会想 万一
And sometimes, I mean, I do think if it ends up
我真的不在了 只剩她孤身一人
that she's alone in that house...
她就谁也没有了 她跟我爸彼此憎恨
She has no one. She and my dad hate each other.
他也没什么姐妹
She has no siblings.
我不知道他该怎么办
I don't know what she'd do.
不要哭
Don't cry.
我没哭
I'm not crying.
哦 也是 不过你想哭的话 可以哭
Right, well, you know, you can cry if you need to.
你刚才不是说“不要哭”吗
I thought you said, "Don't cry."
我和我爸以前会在街区散步
Me and my dad used to walk around the block
一起数松鼠
and count squirrels.
为什么？他在什么松鼠人口普查部门工作吗
Why? Did he work for, like, the squirrel census?
没有啦 我们只是在一起的时候
No, it was just something we did
会找点事做
when it was time for us to spend time together.
我们数的时候甚至都不跟彼此聊天
We didn't even say anything while we did it.
就说数字:
All we'd say was stuff like:
"7只松鼠" "又两只 9只"
"Squirrel, seven." "Two squirrels, nine."
天啊 你该立刻申请个爸爸偿还基金
Jesus. You need to apply for a dad refund immediately.
我是哪个团体的？
What group am I in?
啥？
What?
你昨天不是说 你根据团体
Yesterday you were saying you'd mapped out
划分了整个学校吗？
the entire high school by group.
我是哪个团体的？
What's my group?
- 你认真的？ 是啊
Seriously? Yeah.
无聊的犹太高三女生小团体2-A
Boring Jewish Senior Girls, Subgroup 2-A.
求你欣赏一下我刚刚有多诚实吧
Please appreciate how honest I was just now.
你真是个混蛋
You're an asshole.
经典电影* 你是哪个团体的？
What group are you in?
我没有加入任何团体
Uh, I'm not in a group, actually.
反正不逊的团体我都加入不起
I just wouldn't belong to a group that doesn't suck.
你知道的 我总是超囧
You know, I'm terminally awkward
丑得像只土拨鼠
and I have a face like a little groundhog.
所以...
So...
你不该这么想的
You can't really think that.
不啊 我不是要这么想
No, I don't think that.
我这叫有自知之明
I know that.
我只是觉得 像我这样的孩子
I just feel like, you know, for a kid like me...
在高中 为了生存
...in high school, best case scenario,
这是最好的模式，明白？
just... survive. You know?
不去招惹天敌
Survive without creating any mortal enemies...
或者干点什么丢人事被人记一辈子
...or hideously embarrassing yourself forever.
只是在大学前这样吗?
Just survive until college?
大学? 不 老天 大学会更糟
College? No. God, college is going to be even worse.
什么?
What?
我是说 至少 高中三点就放学了
I mean, at least high school, it's over at 3:00...
而且现在想想 大家都是未成年人 而且都认识
...and it's kids I mostly know by now.
但是大学 完全是无止境地 每天遭遇陌生人
But college is just gonna be non-stop strangers.
有些陌生人甚至要跟你住一个寝室
And some of them even live in your room.
就意味着你永远都无法放松
It's like you can literally never relax.
我都能预见到 不到两周 我可能就会被恐慌压死了
I see myself dying of a panic attack two weeks in.
所以我可能不上大学了
I might just not apply.
这是我听过的你说的最傻的话
That's the dumbest thing I've ever heard you say.
没有吧 我觉得最傻前五都排不上
It's probably not even top five.
而且你看 不管是高中还是大学
And, you know, high school, college,
我们被迫浪费生命中的这么多年
we're forced to spend these years of our lives...
与随机的 全无共同点的这么多人
...in randomly selected groups of people
生活在一起
that we have nothing in common with.
简直是一场噩梦
It's a nightmare.
不这么说的人 都是骗子
Anyone who says otherwise is lying.
恭喜你 Greg
Congratulations, Greg.
明天 你将和无聊的犹太高三女生小团体2-A
Tomorrow, you're eating lunch with
一起吃中饭
Boring Jewish Senior Girls, Subgroup 2-A.
你一般都坐哪儿?
So where do you usually sit?
这真跟在坎大哈吃中午饭没啥区别
It's literally like we're trying to have lunch in Kandahar.
Rachel 我们刚刚想好了今年舞会的主题
Rachel, we just found out the theme for this year's prom:
"骑士难忘夜"
"A Knight to Remember."
加个K 变成骑士 中世纪主题哦
Knight with a "K." Medieval prom!
舞会不是还有6个月才到吗
Isn't prom like six months away?
大家好 这是Greg
Hi, guys. This is Greg,
他今天和我们一起吃饭
he's gonna be sitting with us today.
有人要勺子吗?
Anybody need any spoons? No?
哈啰
Hello.
Greg 你今天为什么跟我们一起吃饭？
So, Greg, why are you sitting with us today?
那个 吃午饭嘛
You know, it's lunch.
总得坐在什么地方吃 不能站着吃啊
You gotta eat somewhere. Can't stand and eat.
你和Rachel怎么突然关系这么好
You and Rachel seem very friendly, all of a sudden.
是啊
Yeah.
你跟她聊天只是因为她得了癌症
You're only talking to her because she has cancer.
啥?
What?
Greg 你之前跟Rachel约会过
Greg, you hung out with Rachel once.
你跟她作朋友只是为了让自己心里好受些
You're befriending her to feel good about yourself.
不 不是的
No, I'm not.
谁会这么做啊
Who even does that?
你们介意我坐下吗？
You guys mind if I sit with you?
当然不介意
Of course not.
不好意思 这是...
Sorry, it's a...
这是个枕头 其实我是拿它当婴儿啦
It's a pillow. It's meant to be a baby,
卫生课要用
for health class.
你觉得这玩意在这儿安全么?
You think it's safe here?
一个枕头么?
A pillow?
Greg 你怎么看?
Greg, what do you think?
嗯 我不知道
Mmm, I don't know.
反正别离我太近
Better not get it too close to me,
不然我撸完 可能会射上去哦
otherwise I might just masturbate onto it.
呕 Greg 你怎么这么恶心
Ew, Greg, that's just weird and gross.
我是怎么因为纯粹的尴尬而恐慌的
嘿 各位
Hey, everyone,
快看Scott Mayhew的暴龙步
check out Scott Mayhew's Tyrannosaurus walk.
这是从点A到点B的一种很好的方式！
It's a great way to get from point A to point B.
你这样说太不好了 Greg
That was really mean, Greg.
我觉得他听见你说的了
I think he heard you.
就这样
And just like that...
我八年苦心经营的隐身术
...eight years of carefully-cultivated
就这么 没 了
invisibility... gone.
我完了
Fin.
你妈妈做饼干了?
Your mom made cookies?
没有 这是我从Ill Phil的游戏中赢的
Nah, I won them off of Ill Phil in a game of tonk.
真懒得管你去哪了
Got tired of whooping your sorry ass.
他们干嘛要叫这个
Scholar Horizons Biology? Why do they even call it Scholar Horizons Biology?
应该叫
Scholar Horizons Tonk Maybe they should call it Scholar Horizons Tonk.
或者纸质橄榄球什么的
Or Sometimes Paper Football.
小鬼们
Heathens.
- 你们好吗？ - 嗨 McCarthy先生
What up? Hi, Mr. McCarthy.
哇哦
Wow.
Earl 给你说个事实 你们的午饭真是垃圾
Earl, fact, that lunch is garbage.
你吃这个 简直就是在我们面前服毒
You're literally poisoning yourself right in front of us.
至少我没吃奇奇怪怪的
At least I ain't eating no funky ass
海带触手汤
seaweed-looking tentacle soup.
讲真 这个真的很不错
Seriously, this stuff is the business.
是越南菜 叫河粉
It's Vietnamese. It's called Pho.
实在是“粉好吃”哦
It is "Pho-nomenal."
那让我吃一口呗
Well, let me try some one time.
哼
Mmm.
- 你想吃哦? 是啊
Now you want to try some? Yeah.
不给
Well, no.
校规不允许我给你食物
It's strictly forbidden for me to give you food.
不过 我推荐你去
However, if you go to...
Lawrencewille的一家餐厅
...Thuyen's Super Saigon Flavor
叫“涂云超级西贡风味”
over in Lawrenceville...
就说找涂云
...and ask for Thuyen.
跟他说 算我账上 你们可以在那儿尝尝
Tell him to put it on my tab. You'll be all set.
我才不去什么该死的Lawrenceville.
I ain't going to no damn Lawrenceville.
那没办法
Fair enough.
不好意思 我要走了
You'll have to excuse me.
孩子们
Boys.
尊重研究
Respect the research.
尊重!
Respect!
天啊 你知道吗 人们都觉得
God! You know, people just assume that
我跟Rachel在约会
Rachel and I are dating.
简直毁了我的生活
It's ruining my life.
我今天还威胁要性骚扰一个假婴儿
Today I threatened to sexually assault a fake baby.
而且还跟Scott Mayhew成了天敌
And I became mortal enemies with Scott Mayhew.
这一切都是Rachel的错
Both of which are Rachel's fault.
我不该这么说 但确实是她的错
Sorry, but they just are.
当然了 我这么抱怨简直是混蛋
Of course I'm a dick for complaining about it.
我是说 我这么抱怨确实挺没品的
I mean, I am a dick for complaining about it.
我也不是故意要这样
I didn't actually mean any of that.
你还是跟她玩爱爱吧
Better play with them titties.
你觉得这玩意尝起来奇怪吗？
Does this taste strange to you?
这汤里有毒品！
The soup had drugs.
哇！
Whoa!
这就是我怎么不小心磕了药的
McCarthy先生肯定往汤里放了大麻
McCarthy must've put weed in that soup
因为我的大脑就像要吃了自己一样
because my brain is trying to eat itself.
我的天噜
Oh, my God.
我现在就得去见Rachel
I have to go visit Rachel right now.
好啊 去吧
Okay, well, you do that.
我到时候会在你家 把你爸的食物全都吃掉
I'ma be at your house eatin' up all your dad's food.
别啊 你跟我一起来 帮帮我啊
No! You have to come help!
帮啥？
Help with what?
就帮我嘛！
Help!
嘿 上课时 McCarthy老师是经常有点
Hey, in class, do McCarthy act all, like,
疯疯癫癫像嗑了药的吧?
stoned and shit?
呃 我也不知道 有点吧
Uh, I don't know. I guess.
是 有时候吧
Yeah, sometimes.
不是有时候
Well, not sometimes,
但是你知道我... 你知道他那样子
but you know what I'm... You know how he is.
该死 哥们
Goddamn, son.
你连句完整话都说不出来了
You can't even put a full damn sentence together.
McCarthy先生嗑放了药的汤 简直太疯狂了
It's insane that Mr. McCarthy eats soup with drugs in it.
嘿 哥们 声音小点！
Hey, come on, man, keep your damn voice down.
我们嗑了药这件事 不能告诉任何人
We can't tell anyone we're on drugs.
为啥？
Why the hell not?
因为他们就会知道了
Because then they'll know.
啊 是我们的谦逊小耗子来了
It's my humble little mouse.
小耗子的朋友又是谁?
And who is his little mouse friend?
Earl Jackson
Earl Jackson.
Earl只是我的同事 他人很不错
Earl's just my coworker, and, uh, he's a great guy.
我们只是在附近散步
We were just walking around the neighborhood, you know.
没什么别的事做
Not really doing anything,
所以来打个招呼
and just wanted to come say "What's up?"
因为Rachel就要剃光头发了
'Cause Rachel's about to lose her hair.
嗯 只是过来说一句
Mmm. So, just wanted to say,
"拜拜 头发 终于摆脱你了"
you know, "Bye, hair. Good riddance."
她没头发的样子肯定也超美的 所以...
She's gonna look great without hair. That's a fact, so...
嗯 就是来打个招呼
Yeah, I just wanted to say what's up.
Rachel 你有两个可爱的谦逊小鼠朋友
Rachel! We've got two cute little mouse boys
来看你 想跟你打个招呼
on our doorstep that wanna say hi!
你们两只小耗子 要不要来点奶酪啊?
Would you two... mice like a little bit of cheese?
好呀
Okay.
我喜欢你的房间 Rachel
I like your room, Rachel.
谢谢 Greg总觉得太少女了
Thanks. Greg thinks it's too girly.
没有啦 我喜欢少女 我觉得很棒
No, I love girly, I think it's fine.
不过其实也没有很少女啦
Well, it ain't too girly.
"哟 看 粉粉的毛绒玩意"
"Yo, this some pink puffy bullshit."
我是说 Hello Kitty海报
I mean, Hello Kitty posters
还有巧克力肤色裸男挂满墙
and chocolate and naked dudes all over the wall.
真的让我想吐哦
They make me want to throw up for real.
如果你真的想吐的话 别在这儿好么
Hey, if you're gonna throw up, don't do it in here, okay?
这是她的房间
This is her room.
无所谓了
Anyways.
Rachel 我们真的想来看看你怎么样了
Rachel, we really just wanted to see how you was doin'.
谢了
Thanks.
是啊 化疗 感觉肯定很烂吧
Yeah, chemotherapy. That really sucks.
Greg
Greg.
你怎么回事啊 别说什么烂啊烂的
What the hell, bro? Don't say it suck, dumb-ass!
确实挺烂的啊
It does kinda suck.
是 我是说 这你也避免不了的
Yeah, but I mean, you gotta do what you gotta do.
是吧 大概
Yeah, I guess.
呃...
Um...
Uh...
你们要是不想在这儿 可以走的
Look, you guys can go if you want.
- 我们嗑药了 - 天啊
We're on drugs. Oh, shit!
你们为啥嗑药啊?
Why are you on drugs?
我们不是有意的
Well, we're accidentally on drugs.
"不是有意的"?
"Accidentally"?
McCarthy先生给我们喝了点汤
McCarthy gave us some soup.
是 McCarthy先生给了我们一点他的
Well, McCarthy gave us some of his,
就是 他平常喝的 再正常不过的汤
you know, just regular, normal soup...
但是 结果 那个汤吧不太够...
...but then, it was the last of the soup
所以我们又去一家饭店
so we had to go get some more...
又买了一些
...from a restaurant,
那家饭店在一个办公楼的五楼
on the fifth floor of an office building.
然后同时 牙买加大使馆
And in the same building,
也在那栋楼
there was a Jamaican embassy...
然后我们跟一个苏里南人
...and we ended up getting trapped
被困在一间电梯里
in an elevator with a Rastafarian guy...
...他抽烟抽得整个电梯间都是那味儿
...and he just hotboxed the whole elevator, so...
我们被困在一起大概25分钟
We were stuck in there for, like, 25 minutes...
...所以我们也闻了点大麻
...and we had to breathe the weird marijuana air.
Earl 我说得对吧?
Earl, am I right?
没错 就这样
That's exactly what happened.
你们这一路可真是艰险
You guys had quite an adventure.
嗑药感觉好烂啊
Being on drugs just really sucks.
跟嗑药的人在一起感觉也好烂
Being around people on drugs sucks.
这一切都太烂了 真抱歉
This whole situation, really sorry, just sucks. I'm sorry.
嘿 你什么毛病啊
Yo, yo. What the hell is your problem, man?
干嘛总对不起对不起的
All apologetic and shit,
给你自己找借口
making shit 'bout your sorry ass.
我们来了又不是来道歉的
Look, that's not what we came here to do. Okay?
我们是来帮忙的 带这姑娘出门走走
You wanna help, you gonna take this girl out
吃个冰棍
to get some ice cream.
我也要吃 因为我喜欢吃冰棍
And me, too, 'cause I love that shit.
你喜欢吃吗?
You like ice cream?
喜欢
Yeah.
那 你是从学校里认识Greg的?
So, you know Greg from class?
我们俩从很小的时候就认识了
I've known Greg ever since we were little.
是幼儿园就认识了吧?
You know, I was in y'all kindergarten, right?
真的?
Really?
嗯哼 我记得你
Mmm-hmm. I remember you.
你是那个管Justin叫变态的姑娘
You was the girl who called Justin Jones perverted...
就因为他给姑娘们看他屁股上的胎记
...for showing girls the birthmark on his butt.
天啊 对的！
Oh, my God, yes!
是啊 那家伙跑上来
Yeah, dude came running up,
脱了裤子 你当时可冷静了
showed you his butt. You were calm.
说 "Justin 只有变态才给人看屁股"
Said, "Justin, only perverts show their butts."
我当时在场啊
I was right there.
真不敢相信你还记得
I can't believe you remember that.
你是个英雄啊 阻止了变态暴露狂
You a hero. Shut his perverted ass right down.
我永远都不会忘
I never forget it.
那 你和Greg是同事?
So you and Greg are coworkers?
不 我们是朋友
Naw, we friends.
他只是不喜欢管别人叫朋友 他这人有心理问题
He just hates calling people his friend. Dude's got issues.
确实 怎么回事?
Yeah, he does. What's going on?
我也不知道是为啥 可能是他家人吧
Man, I don't even know. It might be his folks.
我是说 他妈总是跟他说
I mean, dude's mom always tellin' him
他多帅多帅 其实他不帅
how handsome he is, which he ain't.
所以他不相信跟他亲近的人
So now he think he can't trust anybody close to him.
他爹是个怪咖
Dude's weird-ass dad
不跟任何人社交 除了他家史蒂猫
don't socialize with anybody 'cept the cat.
简直是不交朋友的楷模
So that's a role model ain't got no friends.
总而言之 他恐惧
Bottom line, dude's terrified
把别人称为朋友
of callin' somebody his friend...
然后别人说“嘿 哥们 我不是你朋友”
...and they sayin', "Hey, bro, I'm not your friend."
他可能就会自杀了
Then he'd have to kill himself.
但是你们是同事又是什么意思?
But how are you coworkers?
我们一起拍小电影
We, um, we make films.
电影?
Movies?
是 我们合作了好几年了
Yeah. We been making them for a few years now.
到现在一共拍了42部了
We have, like, 42 in total.
Greg! 你都没跟我说过！
Greg! You never told me.
呃 我们谁也没告诉过
Well, we never told anybody 'bout them.
他们很烂的 我是说 真的都很不好看的
They suck. I mean, they're terrible.
我敢肯定它们没那么烂
I'm pretty sure they don't suck.
你要是想看的话可以自己来看啊
Well, you can see for yourself if you want.
真的吗?
Are you sure?
那当然 别担心
Hell, yeah, don't even worry about it.
不过别告诉别人
Just don't tell nobody.
当然 我不会的
No, of course, I won't.
好了 小子 起来吧
All right, son, get on your feet.
听起来不错
Sounds good.
我们要去哪儿?
Where are we going?
《蓝丝绒之酿猴酒》（不是大卫林奇拍的哦）
Earl是怎么把最后的秘密泄露出去的
我们可以送你回家啊
We can walk you home.
他得缓一缓
He needs to recover,
你得照顾他吧
and you probably should look after him.
保重保重
Peace, peace.
- 谢谢 拜拜
Thanks. Bye.
该死 Earl
Goddamn it, Earl.
小子 你啥也别说了
Son, don't even start.
猪蹄 吃吗
Pig's foot.
那啥 这个傻故事 都讲了这么长时间了...
So, we're pretty far into this stupid story now...
你可能在想
...and you're probably saying to yourself,
"我挺喜欢Rachel这姑娘的
"Hey. I like this girl Rachel.
"如果她最后死了的话 我会气死的"
"And I'm gonna be pissed if she dies at the end."
我就剧透算了 别害怕 她活下来了
don't freak out. She survives.
希望这能给你吃个定心丸
So, hopefully, that reassures you.
不过 话说回来 为啥呢
Although, actually, why would it?
我对你们今天的热情感到震撼
I'm just overwhelmed with your enthusiasm today.
所以我们还是
I guess we're just gonna have to do it
来个经典玩法吧
the old-fashioned way.
我会想你们一个人的名字
I'm thinking of one of you.
我不会说是谁
I'm not gonna mention any names,
但是这个人的名字缩写是...
but your initials...
...Scott Mayhew
...are Scott Mayhew.
事实：Greg一直跟大家说
Greg's been telling everyone
你的汤里有大麻
your soup has marijuana in it.
我谁也没告诉
I didn't tell anyone.
我听见你在校车上叨逼叨来着
I heard you bellowing about it on public transit.
这是事实吗 Greg?
Is that a fact, Greg?
是这样 昨天 我和Earl不知怎么嗑嗨了
Look, yesterday, Earl and I got stoned somehow.
就在我俩喝了你的汤之后
And it was after we both ate your soup.
我们两个没有抽大麻
And we didn't smoke any marijuana,
我这辈子也没抽过那个 所以...
which I have never done, so...
你的汤里肯定有大麻
Your soup must have drugs in it,
因为我们就一起吃了那个...
'cause that was the only thing we both ate...
...哦 还有从Ill Phil那儿赢的饼干
...other than some cookies we got from Ill Phil,
那个药贩子
the drug dealer.
啊哈
Aha.
天啊 为什么我们就没想到饼干呢
Man, how did you not know it was the cookies?
是因为你个傻逼在校车上大喊大叫
Man, it was your dumb ass yelling that shit on the bus.
嘿 Greg!
Yo, Greg!
你告我的密了?
Did you snitch on me?
他确实告了你的密!
He did snitch on you!
我当时在场
I was there.
我听到你 跟你的小女生朋友们
I heard you ridiculing me
开我的玩笑
in front of your loathsome harem.
你可给自己树了个天敌
You have made... a mortal enemy.
我永远不会放过你的
And I will never stop hounding you.
是的 你树了两个天敌 我给你讲 我可捅过人
Yeah, you made two mortal enemies. I stabbed a dude.
上帝啊
Jesus.
我会用20种不同方式杀掉你 用刀捅你 射杀你 掐死你...
Rachel去化疗的几周
我说什么呢？
其实他们啥也没干
So they haven't really done anything.
算起来快一个月了
It's been about a month now.
他们确实说了永远不会放过我
They did say they're never gonna stop hounding me...
所以 大概早晚吧
...so, sooner or later... you know...
我都会被他们整的
...gonna get hounded.
对不起 下次我会带点花来
Sorry, next time I'll bring you some flowers.
不过我也不知道要放在哪里
Though I don't even know where I'd put them.
好像只有呕吐筐还是空的了
It's like, like the only place left is the barf bucket.
鲜花
Flowers.
就放在你呕吐的地方
Where you barf.
我喜欢你的帽子
I like that hat.
蛮可爱的
It's pretty cute.
你看 我一直也不是漂亮型的
Look, I've never been very beautiful...
我也觉得没关系 因为我不看重这些
...and that's fine because that's not important to me.
但是...
But...
我本以为自己可以轻松接自己这幅样子
I thought it'd be easier looking like this.
但事实上我接受不了
It's just not.
大家来看我
Everyone comes in here and sees me...
...但却都很明显地抗拒
...and they're so clearly repulsed.
真的比我想象的难多了
It's so much harder than I thought it would be.
嘿 别这么说
Hey, come on.
你很美
You look good.
我很丑的 Greg! 我很丑
I'm ugly, Greg! I'm so ugly.
大家都觉得该对我撒谎
Everyone feels like they have to lie to me and no one
但没人觉得这样有多伤人
realizes how insulting that is.
大家都觉得他们在帮我 但其实没有
Everyone thinks they're helping, and they're not.
给
Here.
这个叫 魔生门
That one's called Mono Rash.
是根据黑泽明的 罗生门 改编的
It's based on Rashomon by Kurosawa.
情节就是Earl一直在杀人
Plot's basically just Earl killing people
因为他生病了 发了疯
'cause he has a rash...
...你知道 就是单核细胞增多症
...from mono, you know, the STD.
不管怎么样吧 我们要开始拍
Anyway, we're supposed to go work on
《现代启示录》的致敬了
our homage to Apocalypse Now.
我们的小电影叫 《现代启示录之哇哦一盒郁金香》
Ours is called A Box O' Lips, Wow,
我觉得比《魔生门》还逊
which is even worse than Mono Rash.
是一部战争片 讲的是两个人
It's a war movie where these two guys
加入了一场难以言说的残忍战争
take part in the unspeakable brutality of war...
...然后找到了一盒郁金香
...and then they find a box of tulips.
《一盒郁金香》嘛 然后他俩就说“哇哦”
Box O' Lips, yeah. And they're just, "Wow."
这盒郁金香实在太美好了 他俩受不了了
They can't get over how great these tulips are,
他俩就说 "哇哦！一盒郁金香诶!"
it's like, "A box o' lips, wow!"
不过最逊的是 郁金香太贵了
The worst part is, tulips might not
我们的成本根本买不起
even be in the budget anymore.
我还是在这儿呆着吧
I should actually just stay here
不该让你看见这种垃圾
and keep you from watching that.
没关系 去拍吧！
No! I'm fine. Go make it.
好
Okay.
好吧 祝你看这部烂片
Okay. Have fun watching
看得愉快
this incredibly terrible movie.
嗯 你也
Mmm. Have fun
- 拍片愉快 - 嗯哼
making the next one. Mmm-hmm.
嘿 白人男孩!
Hey, white boy!
你给我做一朵郁金香吧 不然我会把Doopie叫来
Why don't you make me a tulip 'fore I have Doopie come down
让他生吃了你
there and eat your face?
不是 说真的 你能给我做朵郁金香吗？
But no, for real. Can you make me a tulip?
我的天啊 我在片场吗？
Oh, my God! Am I on set right now?
- 该死! 我的天
Oh, damn! Oh, my God!
啊啊啊 好激动 开机！停机！
Ahh! I can't take it! Action! Cut!
Madison 你来这干嘛?
Madison, why are you here?
Rachel说我能在这找到你
Rachel said that I could find you here...
...你电话直接转语音信箱了
...and your phone was going straight to voice mail.
大概是因为这里一点信号都没!
Probably 'cause there ain't no good service down there!
但是我得来 我得跟你说件事
But I had to get here 'cause I had to let you know.
是这样 我去看Rachel 给她送慰问卡
So, I was visiting Rachel, and I was giving her a card...
她正在看你的一部小电影
...and she was watching one of your secret movies.
天啊 你也看到了？
Oh, my God. Wait, did you see any of it?
没有 她立马就关掉了
No! No, she turned it off immediately.
我觉得挺好看的
It was good, it was good.
就是 你俩都是日本人...
You know, you're both Japanese, and...
然后Earl砍你的头
...Earl beheaded you, and, but then,
然后她就关掉了
she, like, turned it off.
但是我有个想法 一个很赞的想法
But I had a brainstorm. Okay? I had an amazing brainstorm.
我想 你应该给Rachel拍部电影
I realized... you need to make a film for Rachel.
你怎么想?
What do you think?
那会是她在这世上最喜欢的东西
It would be like her favorite thing in the entire world...
也会是你人生中做过的最重要的一件事
...and it's like the most important thing you could do.
你一定得答应
You have to do it.
好吧 保证
Yeah, word.
"保证"? 意思是 你同意了？
"Word"? Like, word, you'll do it, word?
是的
Yep.
天啊 太好了!
Oh, my God, awesome!
那啥 等不及看你的成片了！
Okay, well, I can't wait to see it.
呃 好吧 我要走了 那...
Um, okay, I gotta go, but...
停!
Cut!
杀青!
That's a wrap!
别停!
Rolling!
女人啊
Titties.
该死!
Goddamn it!
在接下来的几周里
In the next few weeks,
我开始拍这电影了么？ 没有
did I start making that movie? No.
因为我并不同意拍这部片
Because I didn't agree to make that movie.
我只是说了“保证”而已
All I said was, "Word."
也可以什么意义都没有啊
"Word" could mean anything.
还有 在Rachel看完我们的烂片之前
Plus, we had at least a month or two...
大概只剩一个多月了
all the terrible films we'd already made.
比如 《袜条橙》
For example, A Sockwork Orange.
"Droogle"?
是流氓们用的谷歌
It's Google for droogs.
那是什么?
What's that?
没什么 只是我的死对头
Nothing, just the bane of my existence.
我妈妈逼着我一直带着这本书
Which my mom is forcing me to carry around
直到我找到好大学申请
until I apply to some colleges.
她说 这玩意就像是
She says it's like a menu
写满我未来的菜单 我想 "那是
for my future, and I was, like, "Sure.
"一个只有在接下来四年里
"A menu that only has food
"无休止地羞辱我的食品的菜单"
"that will humiliate me for four years."
你在大学的问题上能不能别这么傻
You have to be less of an idiot about college.
听着 如果你觉得人们不喜欢你
Listen, even if you think people won't like you...
这想法本来就很荒唐
...which is literally an insane thing to think...
...你在大学里不用在人群中暴露很多的
...you're way less exposed to people in college.
高中一周课大概40小时
High school is 40 hours of class a week.
大学只有15到20小时
College is, like, 15 and 20.
如果你不想住校的话
And if you don't want to live with other people,
那去匹茨堡州立大学啊
then go to Pittsburgh State.
这样就可以走读了
Live at home.
总比因为你不理智地讨厌自己
It's better than sitting college out
而不上大学好吧
because you irrationally hate yourself.
我没有不理智
Not irrationally, though.
申请匹茨堡州立大学吧
Apply to Pittsburgh State.
现在就申请 早点申请
Right now. Apply early.
来 现在就当着我的面申请 申请匹茨堡州立大学
Come on. Do it in front of me. Apply to Pittsburgh State.
如果我说不呢?
What if I say no?
我癌症四期了
I have stage four cancer.
所以你要是拒绝 就是个混蛋
So that would be a pretty dick move. Come on.
好吧
Fine.
"为什么我想上大学"
"Why I want to go... to college."
作者 沃纳·赫尔佐格
By Werner Herzog.
高度选择性的
The highly selective
招生过程...
admissions process...
...剔除那些残忍和愚蠢的学生
...weeds out the cruel and the stupid.
因此大学并不像高中那样
So college is unlike the senseless chaos...
是完全的病态 无序的混乱
...and sickening enormity of high school.
高中像是恶魔的嘴巴
High school is the mouth of a great demon...
撕咬 咀嚼
...biting and chewing
将人折磨得体无完肤
and smushing people in the face.
真是无法忍受
It is simply overwhelming.
好了 十分庄重地说
In all seriousness,
我很期待大学生活
I am looking forward to college...
因为高中并不适合我
...because I didn't really fit in in high school,
因为我丑得像耗子
because of my weird rodent face...
才没有
No.
...并且有种说世界上最傻的话的习惯
...and a habit of saying the dumbest possible shit.
才没有!
No!
我的发青的面色
The sheer pastiness of my complexion...
让人看了就想吐
...overwhelms all who behold it with existential nausea.
"在高中 我从未在自己身上
"In high school, I never truly felt comfortable...
"感觉舒适
"...in my own skin.
"实际上 我是那种...
"In fact, I've always been someone...
"不怎么喜欢自己的人
"...who doesn't really like themselves.
"但我认为 我还要成长的
"But I think that's because I have some growing up to do...
"...所以大学是个合适的地方"
"...and college is the place where I'm going to do it."
这也太私人了吧
That's way too personal.
本来就是个人的论文啊
好吧 那你还想看这个吗...
Fine, if you want to see this again...
好吧！好吧！
Okay! Okay!
只是因为你的癌症
But only because cancer.
还有 猜怎么着 你也得跟我一样
And you know what? You have to do this too now. Here.
翻翻这本可怕的大部头
Page through this huge, horrible book
找到你想申请的大学
and find some colleges.
轮到你了
That's yours now.
嗯哼 就像是写满你未来的菜单
Mmm. It's like a menu for your future.
我能先看完电影吗?
Can I finish my movie first?
失败的友谊：第64天
失败的友谊：第71天
失败的友谊：第85天
这样 如果我们拍了这部电影
So, if we make this film,
人们会说:
people are gonna be, like:
"哦 Greg今儿Earl
"Oh, Greg and Earl,
"他们就是那俩怪兮兮的电影人
"they're those weird filmmakers.
"总是神神秘秘地拍东西
"They're always creepily filming stuff.
"可能某天晚上他们会溜进你家
"They'll probably sneak into your house one night
"拍你睡觉的样子"
"and film you while you're sleeping."
但大家可能已经开始这么想了
But people probably already think that,
所以现在我变得这么多疑 - 真难吃
So now, I've become completely conspicuous,
一直紧张
like all the time.
人们会看着我 然后想
People look at me and think,
"拍电影的" - 这什么玩意啊
"Filmmaker." The hell even is this?
人们已经认为我是
When they're not already thinking,
"那个癌症女的男朋友"
"Cancer girl's boyfriend."
吃着就像狗的屁眼
It tastes like a dog's funky-ass butthole.
此外 我们还同意拍一部
Furthermore, we agreed to do a film
我们也不知道会是什么样的
that we have no idea what it should look like...
电影
...or sound like, or even be.
我是说 我连拍什么类型
I mean, what the hell sort of film
都还不知道 该拍啥呢？
should we even make? Huh?
我都不知道自己真么想的?
I mean, what was I thinking?
你在想那个美女Madison
You were thinking that girl Madison
有对漂亮的奶头
had nice titties.
我是说 我也喜欢奶头
I mean, I like the titties too,
但这是你的问题
but now you got a problem.
因为可不是我同意拍这个的
'Cause I ain't agreed to do this shit.
是你同意的
You did.
你不帮我拍吗？
Are you not gonna help me make this?
我们拍啥呢 小子
The hell we gonna make, son?
他们想要新鲜的灵感
They want fresh inspiration.
我必须告诉你 我得到过的
I must tell you, the richest inspiration
最丰富的灵感是
I have ever known was...
...我在亚马逊被隔离的那段时间
...during my period of quarantine in the Amazon.
我当时跟其他六七个人被困
Where I and a half dozen other...
满目都是各种
...unfortunates had nothing to watch...
大狼蛛
...but the bristling, leviathan tarantula...
爬上腐烂的茅草棚
...bunched up on the rotting, flimsy thatch...
离我们的脸只有大概8英尺
...perhaps eight feet above our faces.
那蜘蛛有拳头那么大
Spiders the size of your fist.
他们的尖牙闪烁着毒液
Their fangs glistening with venom and...
几千个黑色的复眼
...their thousand-fold black eyes
在昏暗中闪着呆滞的光芒
shining dully in the gloom.
在黑暗中 你甚至能听见
In the darkness, you would hear
突然的痛苦嘶叫
the sudden anguished hiss...
那是蜘蛛被豹蜂困住的声音
...of a spider being struck by an adult leopard wasp...
在他们的挣扎过程中
...and in their mortal struggle,
他们会骤降到某人的床上
they would plummet to one's bed...
咬啊 叮啊...
...biting and stinging and thrashing...
你知道马蜂也可以熏烤着吃吗?
You know that you can smoke a hornet?
那这样 你回答问题的时候看我就好
Okay, so just look at me when you answer the questions.
不要担心镜头 好吧?
Don't worry about the camera, all right?
好 Denise
Okay, Denise.
给我讲讲Rachel的出生吧
Tell me a little about Rachel's birth.
呃 Rachel的出生...
Uh, Rachel's birth.
那是多么难熬的经历啊
What an ordeal that was.
Greg 我就跟你说一件事
Greg, just... let me tell you one thing.
对她来说 我是个好妈妈 知道吗?
I was a really good mom to her, you know?
我真的是个好妈妈
I really was.
有些单身母亲 她们的孩子成长得太过迅速了
Some single moms, their kids grow up too fast...
但我极力保护Rachel
...but I always tried to protect Rachel from that.
我尽了最大的努力
I did my very best to protect her from...
...保护她 让她成长得慢些 明白吗?
...growing up too quickly, you know?
嗯
Right.
但现在 我懂得了有些事情
And now, I'm learning that there are...
你是根本保护不了她的
protect your kid from, you know?
无论你多努力 就是不能...
No matter what you do, you just...
那 她有最喜欢的玩具吗?
So, did she have any favorite toys?
在回答这个问题之前 我讲点认真的
Before I answer that question, this is serious...
所以你给我好好听着
...so use your ears and listen to me.
我想让你保证一件事
I want you to promise me something
因为我很在乎你
as I care about you.
你要保证 除非你
You gotta promise me you're not gonna have a baby...
非常非常爱你的另一半
...unless you're ready to love
否则不会要孩子
that baby's mother your whole life...
我是认真的
...and this is serious.
我给你讲的是独家秘笈
I'm telling you something that nobody's gonna tell you.
不要找善变的姑娘
Don't pick a girl who's push-pull, you know?
要找一个全身心爱你的
You wanna pick somebody who's gonna love you...
不会忘了你的
...and not forget you, and not...
不会扔下你独自一人的姑娘
...leave you for someone with a big, fat ass.
那 最喜欢的玩具是啥
So, no favorite toy.
呃...
Um...
哦 她还真有最喜欢的玩具
Oh, you want to know what? Here's a favorite toy.
剪刀
Scissors.
Rachel的爸爸刚离开我们的时候
When Rachel's father first left...
她收集了他所有的书
...she gathered up all his books,
把它们捆在一起 然后把它们都剪了
...and she rounded 'em up and she cut them right up.
请你别跟她说是我告诉你的
Please, don't tell her I'm telling you,
她会剪掉我的头的
she would chop my head off.
但她...
But she just...
我就想 "干得好 姑娘"
And I was, like, "Atta girl."
咔嚓 咔嚓 咔嚓 她当时好生气
Snip, snip, snip. She was very mad.
我们能不能休息一下 喝点酒什么的？
Can we take a little break and have a little taste?
你们的年龄足够喝酒了吧？
You boys are old enough to have a little taste, right?
我们就休息一小会儿 然后喝点酒吧?
Can we take a teeny break, just have a little taste?
好嘞 好孩子
Oh, yeah, that's a good boy.
Greg 你一起吗?
Greg, will you join us?
哦 算了
Oh, I'm okay.
来吧 不要扫兴! - 好吧
Oh, come on, don't be a party pooper!
现在我们接着采访吧
Now we can get back to our interview.
所以呢 这个拍法是这样
So, basically, this whole setup
就这样 你明白...
is so that, you know...
我能跟你说话 你也能跟我说
...I can talk to you, you can talk to me...
我能看见你 你也能看见我
...and I can see you, and you can see me.
不过其实对面不是我 是个手机
Except it's not really me, it's a phone.
我知道这听起来挺怪的
And I know that sounds kind of weird,
但是其实不怪的
but it's not.
所以呢 就像是个慰问卡一样的
So, anyway, just treat it like a get-well card,
你们可以看着镜头
you can look into the lens.
然后 呃...
And, uh...
就是个小视频嘛...
Yeah, it's a video, so you know...
不要太把它当回事
...don't think about it too hard,
就说点好的就可以了
but just make it good.
准备好了就开始吧
Start whenever you're ready.
嗨 Rachel
Hi, Rachel.
我跟你好像不太熟
I guess I don't really know you that well...
但是我看好你哟 你一定可以的
...but I believe in you. You can do it.
说得挺好的
That's real nice, yo.
你男朋友为你拍视频
It's so sweet that your boyfriend
真的太甜了
is doing this for you.
他一定很爱你
He must really love you.
姑娘 他不是她男朋友
Girl, that ain't her boyfriend.
哦
Oh.
我知道你是犹太人 所以只是想让你知道
I know you're Jewish, but I just wanted you to know
上帝为你安排好了计划
that God has a plan for you.
我觉得你挺酷的
You seem like a really cool person.
我们没怎么说过话
I know we don't really talk.
但是反正你朋友也挺多的
But you've got a lot of friends. And, uh...
学校里这么多人
Out of all the people in this school,
我不讨厌你
I don't hate you.
我看好你哟 你可以的
I believe in you and you can do it.
你可以的
You can do it.
我看好你哟
I believe in you.
你可以
You can do it.
妈的
Damn.
《午后牛仔之2点48》
所以 再说一次
So again,
如果这是个浪漫感人的琼瑶故事
if this was a touching, romantic story...
我们可能就会陷入热恋
...we'd obviously fall in love
她就会在弥留之际 说些智慧之言
and she'd say all the wise, beautiful things...
或者很美的告白 之类的
in life's twilight or whatever.
然后她会在我的臂弯中死去
And then she'd die in my arms.
但 再说一次 事实并不是这样的
But again, that's not what happened.
她只是越来越安静 越来越不开心
She just got quieter. And unhappier.
你好吗？
So, how are you?
说真的
For real.
说真的?
For real?
我觉得你可能是对的
Feeling like you might have been right.
什么对的?
Right when?
十月的时候
Back in October.
你不是觉得我会死嘛
When you thought I was dying.
呃 我很后悔那么想
Well, I mean, I regret thinking that.
不要后悔
Don't regret it.
这什么声音?
What is that noise?
是很后悔的北极熊的声音
It's Regretful Polar Bear.
北极熊拥有着动物王国中
Polar Bears have the purest expression
最纯粹的后悔的表达方式
of regret in the animal kingdom.
你听他们那余音绕梁的哀怨咆哮
Just listen to how haunting and plaintive they sound.
你能别让我笑么 挺疼的
Don't make me laugh. Please. It kinda hurts.
好吧
All right.
我觉得沉默在这儿挺瘆人的
Kind of a monster silence in here.
是
Yeah.
我们沉默一会儿也没什么的
It's okay to just be silent for a while.
你看
Look,
我知道你可能已经在说服自己 这个你们都非常喜欢的
I know you're really bracing for this sweet girl...
甜美女孩 马上就要死了
...that you probably like a lot to die.
但是 请忍一忍好吗？ 她并没有 她的情况好转了
Just please bear with me. She doesn't. She gets better.
我保证
I promise.
整个冬天 我唯一记得的
Pretty much all I remember from that winter...
就是拍这部傻里傻气的电影
...is working on that stupid film...
就是明知道自己什么都拍不好
that made some kind of sense...
却还是想拍点好东西出来
...and knowing the whole time that I couldn't...
想拍点我们想拍的东西
to make the thing we wanted to make...
不过对于我们来说 真的办不到
...but it wasn't possible for us.
失败的友谊：第149-159天 这就是我的整个寒假
That was an entire winter of my life.
我是说 当然
I mean, obviously,
我也记得去看Rachel
I remember visiting Rachel too.
她有时候会跟我聊天
Sometimes she talked,
有时她却不想说话
and sometimes, she didn't want to.
她不想说的时候 就换我说
When she didn't want to, I talked.
或者我们一起看电影
Or we watched movies.
有时候她会笑
Sometimes, she laughed.
有时候不会
Sometimes, she didn't.
我不记得的是 我跟本就放弃了学习
What I don't remember is doing schoolwork.
我当时完全不去上学了
I did literally zero schoolwork during this time.
我没有夸张
Not figuratively.
真的不上学了
Literally zero schoolwork.
那对我来说 其实挺难的
That's actually sort of hard to do.
那么 学校现在是什么样的呢?
So, what's going on at school?
此时此刻 学校就像一座城堡
Well, right now, the whole school looks like a castle...
因为每个人都在
...'cause everyone's getting ready
为中世纪舞会做准备
for Medieval Prom.
我猜学校里的每个人都在想着怎样
I guess everyone's trying to figure out how to, like...
穿着中世纪服装跳电臀舞
...twerk medievally?
你会去吗?
Are you going?
当然不去了
No, of course not.
你应该去
You should go.
才不!
No way!
你见过我穿西装吗?
Have you seen me in a tux?
就像强迫一只狗穿人的衣服一样
It's like when they make a dog wear human clothes.
你见过吗?
Have you seen that?
真的 看起来超可悲的
It just makes you really sad to look at.
哦 还有 根本没人和我一起去
Oh, and I don't have anyone to go with.
所以咯
So there's that.
除非...
Unless...
你...想跟我一起去
...you know... you wanted to...
Greg 我才不去舞会
Greg, I'm not going to prom.
我是觉得 你完全可以去啊
I mean, you totally could.
可以算是一个超棒的宣言
It could be like a, s-, awesome statement.
嘿
Hey, uh...
你们电影啥时候拍完?
When are you guys finishing your movie?
你才不知道我们现在在拍电影
You don't know we're working on a movie right now.
你别装了
You don't have to pretend.
Earl告诉我你们在为我拍一部电影
Earl told me you guys were making a movie for me.
天啊...是...
God, yeah...
好吧 他说的
I guess he probably did.
我问你 是因为...
I was just asking, because...
该死 Earl!
Goddamn it, Earl! Ugh.
只是 我想把这电影作为一个惊喜
It was just, it was supposed to be a surprise!
这电影真的花了很长时间
You know? It's taking forever
因为我们想拍得好一点
because we really want to get it right, and...
我可能马上就要停止治疗了
I'm probably gonna stop treatment pretty soon.
什么?
What?
因为完全没有
It just isn't doing me any good.
只会让我更难受
All it's doing is making me sicker.
是 但是...我是说 如果停止治疗的话...
Yeah, but it... I mean, if you stop, then...
我也不知道 等着看吧
Well, we'll just see what happens.
我们都知道会发生什么 是吧?
Well, we know what's gonna happen, right?
我想到一个人 你可以带着去舞会
I know who you can take to prom.
谁?
Who?
这个性感的枕头
This sexy pillow here.
我的天啊 你能不能--
Oh, my God, can you just...
哦哦哦 Greg
Ooh, Greg,
这个枕头叫Francesca
this pillow's name is Francesca.
别开玩笑 我没心情
Don't joke, I can't deal with that.
她是个来自意大利的蛇蝎女人
She's a filthy Italian woman.
求你了 停下!
Please, stop!
别吼我
Don't yell at me.
所以 就这样了? 什么大学
So, that's it? Just, to hell with college,
什么成长 都不要了?
to hell with growing up?
Greg 别这么说
Greg, don't.
Rachel 你这人怎么回事?
Rachel, what the hell is wrong with you?
这是你的生活!
This is your life!
是 这是我的生活
Yeah, it is my life.
是我必须每天躺在床上
It's me who has to lie in bed all day,
剃了难看的光头
with a shaved head...
越来越丑 越来越虚弱
...getting weaker and uglier,
越来越痛苦 看不到希望
and more miserable, with no hope in sight.
我才是承受这一切的人
I'm the one who has to suffer through this,
不是你 所以你别吼我
not you, so don't yell at me.
对不起 可是我做不到
I'm sorry, but I'm not gonna sit here
就坐在这里看你死
and get comfortable watching you die.
行吗？我做不到
Okay? I'm not. I'm not gonna do that.
所以不要让我这么做
So don't ask me to.
如果你不接受
If you can't accept that I'm going to do
我对我自己生活的选择
what I want to do with my life...
你就是个糟糕的朋友
...then you're a terrible friend.
我是个糟糕的朋友?
I'm a terrible friend?
好吧
Okay.
你知道吗 我才不是那个要放弃一切的
You know, I'm not the one giving up.
我不会放弃一切
I'm not ruining my friend's life
然后毁掉我朋友的生活
by giving up on the whole world.
得了 Greg 你才该兴高采烈吧
Oh, please, Greg, you should be overjoyed.
现在你终于可以回归自己的生活
Now you can go back to your life
在学校里当个
of being invisible and detached...
隐身的 讨厌自己的无名氏吧
...and self-hating.
是
Yeah.
然后你也可以回归你自己的生活 然后死翘翘
And you can go back to your life of being dead.
说得太好了
Nice. Really nice.
这会让你妈难受死的
This is gonna kill your mom.
你愿意看她这样吗?
Have you gotten comfortable with that?
还是你根本就不在乎?
That doesn't bother you anymore?
不在乎你妈妈?
Thinking about your mom?
滚出去 Greg
Get outta here, Greg.
你尽了你的责任了
You've done your time.
你不用再违心跟一个病姑娘一起玩了
You don't have to hang around with the sick girl anymore.
你怎么能对我这么说?
How can you even say that to me?
是你妈妈逼你来看我
Your mom forced you to hang out with me.
是Earl逼你给我看你们的电影
Earl forced you to show me your movies.
Madison 逼你拍一部给我的电影
Madison forced you to make a movie about me.
所以 跟我在一起的哪一部分是你真正愿意的?
So, what part of this did you actually want to do?
你能不能 就为我做一件事
Just... Just do something nice for me for once
就是滚出去
and just get out.
Earl!
咱俩完了! 你太过分了!
This is it! You've gone too far!
你泄露了不能说的秘密
You've leaked the unleakable secret
因为你什么秘密也守不住
because you hold nothing sacred.
因为你是个混蛋!
'Cause you're a dickhead!
任何良好的合作关系
The foundation of any
的基础 都是信任
good working partnership is trust...
而我再也不能信任你了
...and I can no longer trust you in any way.
你什么秘密都跟别人说
You'll leak anything to anyone.
就像跟朱莉安·阿桑奇一起工作
It's like working with Julian Assange.
阿桑奇 混蛋阿桑奇！ 该死!
Assangde. Ass-andge. Damn it!
我们是怎么开始我们生命中的第一次争吵
你想干嘛?
The hell you want?
-我等Earl - 好好好
Just waiting for Earl. Awright, awright.
你好啊孩子 要进来吗?
Whassup, boy? You gonna come in?
是这样 Rachel告诉我说 你告诉她...
So, Rachel told me that you told her about the, uh...
...我们要拍一部给她的电影
...about the film that we're making for her.
你简直是告密的朱利安·阿桑奇
You're like Julian Assange, man.
你总是这样
It's like you always do this...
我真是不懂 因为你想
I don't know, 'cause you, like,
想当个比我更好的朋友吗？
wanna be a better friend than me or something?
我不知道在你混蛋地出卖我之后
I don't know if I can work with you again
我还能不能和你一起工作!
after you sell me out like a dick!
好吧 你小心
Oh, okay. Watch out, yo.
嘿 闭上你的臭嘴!
Hey, yo, shut your ass up, man!
你干嘛总是在乎别人想什么
Like you care so much about what other people think,
你一天吊儿郎当的
boy, you go around here...
讨好这个讨好那个
...kissin' everybody ass,
听着 根本没人在乎你 Greg!
Look, nobody gives a shit about you, Greg!
明白不？ 没人在乎！
All right? Nobody give a shit!
揍他!
Whoop his ass!
然后 有一天 突然出现了这么个 在乎你的姑娘
And then the one girl who do actually care about you...
你却来这儿
...you wanna come over here and
跟我抱怨什么电影?
bitch and whine about some films, yo? Huh?
你抱怨是因为有人在乎你吗?
Because somebody actually cares about you?
该死 我真是烦死你了
Like, damn, I'm so tired of you
你对她好像是你的负担一样
treating this girl like she a burden.
你明白吗 她马上就要死了!
You know, her life is over after this!
你却跑过来
And you want to come over here
跟我抱怨这些八竿子打不着的!
bitchin' and whinin' about some irrelevant bullshit!
你最好离我远点 否则我真的要打你了!
Like, yo, you so close to me knocking your shit loose right now, son!
来啊!
Go for it!
- 我才不在乎! 你想让我打你吗？
Yeah, I don't care! You want me to hit you now?
是的 Earl 我想!
Yeah, Earl, I want you to!
这才对! 把这小鬼打趴下!
That's right! Jack that little dude up there!
看见没 Greg?
See, Greg?
还好是他打的你 不是我
You lucky that was him and not me out there...
不然我会追着你满街跑
...'cause I'd have been whooping your ass up and down this street.
绝对把你打出翔来 明白？
It'd have been a ass-whoopin' fest around here, you dig?
这么说 你20页的尼克松论文写得怎样了?
So what's the status on the 20-pager on Nixon?
呃 能再宽限几天吗
Uh, I need another extension.
应该不太可能了
That might prove difficult...
马上就到期末了
...seeing how it's the...
没法再延了
...the end of the quarter and all.
我知道 我只是很忙
Yeah, I've just been busy.
这样 我听说了一些
You know, I heard...
Rachel的事
...about Rachel.
你还好吗?
How you holding up?
你知道的...
You know...
...不好
...not great.
你知道吗 Greg 我爸在15岁的时候去世了
You know, my dad died when I was 15, Greg.
比你这时候还小几岁
A couple years younger than you.
但是 当我还是个孩子的时候
You know, the thing is that, when I was a kid...
我唯一能记起来的
...I really, I really can only remember
关于他的事情
thinking about him as this...
就是 他是个彻彻底底的大混蛋
...you know, big, kind of like asshole guy.
在守灵式上 他的朋友们
At his wake, these buddies of his
会过来找我说话
kept coming up to me...
给我讲很多他的故事
...and telling me these stories about him.
他们说的那些
And it was like they were talking about
对我来说 完全是另外一个人
some complete other guy.
比如
To give you an example.
他会唱每一首七十年代的
He knew every single European pop song
流行歌曲
from the 1970s.
他学会那些歌
He'd memorize these songs,
好在酒吧里
and he'd do that so he could go...
给德国姑娘们唱
...and sing them to German girls in bars.
他有自己的最爱
He had a go-to,
他的K歌首选
his number one go-to song. It was a...
是一首德语歌 叫Ding-a-Dong
It was a Dutch song. It was called Ding-a-Dong.
我爸经常给酒吧里的德国姑娘们唱这歌
My dad used to sing that to German girls in bars.
这是事实
That's a fact.
你说这些是什么意思？
So what does that mean?
Greg 我只是说
Well, Greg, I think that it just means that...
即使一个人已经不在这世上
...even after somebody dies, you can...
你仍然可以了解他们的不同侧面
...you can still keep learning about them.
他们的生活
You know, their life.
会一点一点地向你展现
It can keep unfolding itself to you just as long...
只要你真正留心注意
...just as long as you pay attention to it.
你真的要把这变成
Are you seriously trying to turn this
愚蠢的伤感课程吗?
into some stupid sappy lesson?
你是个好孩子 Greg
You're a good kid, Greg.
不! 听着 我要回家了
No! Look, I'm going home.
我要当着你的面逃课 看见没?
See, I'm cutting class right in front of you. 'Kay?
我不是个好孩子！不是！
I'm not a good kid. I'm not.
好吧
Okay.
Earl刚来过 送了点东西给我们
Earl came by earlier to drop something off...
但是他拒绝了我做的
...but he turned down this superb
超级超级美味的熏辣兔肉肠
Andouille rabbit sausage...
有点反常
...which is quite unlike him.
你们没事吧?
Is everything all right?
哥们?
Buddy?
我不干了
嗨 Rachel 我们尝试了很多种方式
We tried a lot of different ways
给你拍一部电影
of making a film for you...
但是都太傻气 太没意思了
...but they were all too goofy or irrelevant...
也不是我们想要的效果
...or just not what we wanted.
所以 我就跟你直说了我的心里话吧
So, now I'm gonna talk to you directly.
呃...
Um...
好吧 我说实话了啊
All right, I'm gonna be honest here. Okay?
我觉得 有些时候 白人女孩真的很傻
Sometimes, white girls are particularly stupid.
我是说 这是个傻逼的世界 但是白人姑娘
I mean, everybody's stupid, but white girls, you know...
都觉得自己高别人一等
They think they better than everybody
超级以自我为中心 还假装没有
and self-centered and pretend they not.
但是...
But...
你不是那样的
you aren't like that, you know. Um...
你的耐心让我惊叹
It's just crazy how patient you've been.
如果患癌的是我
You know, I know if it was me that had cancer, uh...
我会超级苦恼 超级生气
...I'd be upset and angry
大部分时间会想暴揍每一个人
and trying to beat everybody's ass half the time.
所以我真的很惊叹于你的耐心
So I'm just, I'm just amazed at how patient you've been.
你让我觉得我很幸运
You, you make me feel blessed.
By Michael Powell
and Emeric Pressburger.
I think, ultimately,
what one has to understand
watching this film...
哦
...it's a very special
piece of filmmaking.
Oh.
你还在这里吃午饭吗?
Are you eating lunch in here still?
你在的话我就不在了
Not if you are.
没关系 你在这吃的话那我就不在了
Well, I'm not eating lunch in here if you are.
那好 我挺喜欢这里的
Good, 'cause I like it in here.
那 我就走了
So I guess I could just go.
或者你走
Or you could go.
不 我要待在空调房
No, I like the air-conditioner.
这椅子也很舒服
And I like the comfortable chair.
是啊 我也喜欢
Yeah, I like those too.
那就是你的问题了
Sounds like your damn problem.
Which showed
one film per week...
...twice a night,
and three times on Saturday.
In a way,
Tales of Hoffmann is...
...the culmination of
Powell-Pressburger's work...
...with what they call
the composed film.
嘿!
Hey!
我能跟你谈谈电影的事吗?
Can I talk to you about the movie?
呃...
Um...
还没拍完呢
Yeah, it's not done yet.
Greg 你们都在一起拍了
Greg, you guys have been working on it
大概四个月了
for like four months.
是...
Yeah, well...
我也说不好 我们一起试了很多种方式
I don't know, we tried a bunch of stuff
但是...
and it just...
就是不怎么管用
...didn't really work.
不够好
It's not that good.
Greg!
现在不是你说 "大家好 我是Greg 我好烂
Now is not the time for your "I'm Greg, I suck,
"我啥事都干不好" 的时候
"nothing I do is any good" thing.
我敢肯定你的电影很棒
I'm sure what you have is awesome
而且如果你早点搞完 给Rachel看的话
and I think she would really benefit...
她一定可以吸取正能量
...if you just got it done and gave it to her.
Madison 她停止化疗了
Madison, she stopped treatment.
她放弃了
She gave up.
她退出了
She quit.
那你就更应该
Well, I guess that's a really good reason
早点弄完你的电影
to just finish the fucking movie.
然后放给她看！
And give it to her.
不过无所谓了
But whatever.
亲爱的?
Honey?
干嘛?
What?
Rachel又住院了
Rachel's back in the hospital, honey.
等等 你是说她又开始化疗了?
Wait, is she starting treatment again?
不是的 亲爱的
It's not for treatment, honey.
哦
Oh.
妈 怎么了?
Mom, what?
我只是觉得我们应该过去
Well, I thought we could go and...
你要抓住这最后的机会 逼我跟她一起玩?
To force me to hang out with her?
Greg 别这样
Greg, come on.
别担心 妈 我肯定
Don't worry, Mom, I'm sure you can find
Rachel死后你会再给我找个患癌少女的
another girl with cancer after Rachel dies.
还有
Which, by the way...
这是她自己决定的
...she's decided to do.
她决定要死
She's just decided to die...
那我也可以决定不去看她
...so maybe I can decide not to visit her.
我保证 如果不去看她的话
I promise you, you will regret that...
你会后悔的
...if you don't visit her.
你会遗憾终生的
You'll regret it for the rest of your life.
妈 这你倒没说错
Mom, that's probably true.
但说真的 我还有一大堆破事
But honestly, I have a shitload of things
等着我去后悔
to regret right now.
我后悔明天的傻逼舞会没有舞伴
I regret not having a date for tomorrow's stupid prom.
我后悔我怪里怪气交不到朋友
I regret being too weird to make friends.
还有我超级超级后悔
I definitely regret making
跟Earl拍那堆烂电影
all those shitty films with Earl.
而且我猜你已经看到从匹茨堡大学 来的那封邮件了 是吧?
And I assume you saw the email I got today, from Pitt?
没有? 你偷看我东西的时候
Oh, no? You didn't see it
没看见吗? 看
while you're going though all my shit? Here.
看看
Have a look.
我绝对绝对会后悔
I'm definitely gonna regret
这一学年完全没去上学!
doing literally no school work this year!
天啊 Greg
Oh, my God, Greg.
我知道 录取取消
I know. Admission rescinded,
因为我这一年成绩飞流直下
due to significant change in my academic record.
太好了 明年没大学可上
Oh, well, no college next year.
我估计都要待在家里了 对你来说太烂了
I guess I'll just be home, which sucks for you...
因为这样 你就不能
...because it's gonna be so hard for you
偷看我的东西了
to go through all my stuff.
你能帮我个忙吗 妈?
Can you just do me a favor right now, Mom?
让我一个人静一静 好吗?
Just leave me alone. Okay?
让我坐在这儿后悔吧
Just let me sit here and regret stuff.
我要回想
I'm just gonna think about
我做过的和没做过的
all the things that I've ever done...
所有事情
...and all the things I haven't done
然后狠狠地后悔一场 行不?
and just regret the living shit out of it. Okay?
所有日期都截止了 Victor
All the deadlines have passed, Victor.
他明年要怎么办?
What's he gonna do next year?
他要浪费掉整整一年吗?
He's just gonna waste the year?
他在难过呢 亲爱的
He is grieving, honey.
你让他难过一下嘛
You have to let him grieve.
那我不能干坐着
But I can't just sit by
看他毁掉自己的生活啊
and just let him ruin his life.
宇宙又不会因为
The universe does not operate
一个大学申请而停转!
according to a college deadline!
我能问你件事吗?
Can I ask you something?
不行
Nope.
不 不是你想的那种问题
No. It's not what you think.
我只是想问 舞会就是今晚
It's just that prom is tonight and...
让我问问你吧 这是干嘛?
Let me ask you something. What is this?
你碰我胳膊干嘛?
What is up with the arm touching?
你只是想表现友好吗？
Are you just being friendly,
还是你耍的什么花招
or is this some calculated maneuver...
为了让我满足你的要求?
...to get me to do whatever you want?
你要知道 这种行为
'Cause you have to understand
当一个漂亮性感
what it does when a beautiful, sexy...
还很聪明的女孩
...otherwise thoughtful girl...
触碰一个瘦骨嶙峋 苍白的
...touches the arm of a scrawny, pasty
丑男生的手臂时 意味着什么
groundhog-faced kid.
这是一种残忍的行为
It's an act of cruelty.
你说完了?
Are you done?
是 我说完了
Yeah. Yeah, I'm done.
我受够你了
I'm done with you.
也受够了这部愚蠢的电影
I'm done with this stupid film.
行吗? 我受够了
All right? I'm done.
嘿! 咱俩还没完呢!
Yo! But you ain't done with me!
我回来复仇了！
I'm back for my revenge
直戳进你的鸡鸡
Stab you in the dick
抱歉说脏话了
Pardon my French
真的? 你要直戳我的鸡鸡? 来吧
Really? You're gonna stab me in the dick? Go ahead.
来直戳我的鸡鸡
Stab me in the dick.
只是别玩饶舌好吗?
Just no rapping. Okay? All right?
我要用我紧握的拳头
I'll break your eyeball
打碎你的眼球
with a fist I got clenched
把你摔倒在长凳下面
Shove your body under another bench
不要饶舌了!
Stop rapping!
用我紧握的拳头 把你一嘴牙都打掉
Knock your teeth out with the fist I got clenched
你要是一直饶舌的话 那我走人了
I can't do this if you're gonna rap the whole time.
啊!
Aw!
让开!
Break it up!
Earl!
让开! 让开!
Break it up! Break it up!
你不是在McCarthy先生的办公室
I thought you were eating lunch
吃午饭吗
in Mr. McCarthy's office.
我是在吃午饭 但是他一直在唠唠叨叨
Man, I was, but he all sad talking
说一堆德国音乐之类的事情
about German music and shit.
真是无聊透了
That's boring as hell, man.
看到你们俩打架 我真是既惊喜又失望
I'm surprised and disappointed to see you two fighting.
我看到你回到学校
Phillip, And, Phillip, I'm surprised and disappointed
也是既惊喜又失望
to see you back on school grounds...
你已经被开除了!
...after being expelled!
好吧
All right, man.
请离开学校！
Please leave the premises.
回教室去吧
Back to class.
走吧
Let's go!
Maxwell, Ryan, Soledad
Maxwell, Ryan, Soledad,
别呆着不动了 走吧!
stop gawking and start walking!
Greg!
嘿 姑娘 你看见我打那个娘娘腔没?
Yo, babe! You see me pummel this bitch?
快滚
Come on and keep walking
小心我再打你
'fore I can whoop that ass again, man.
干嘛 Madison?
Madison, what?
今晚和我一起去舞会吧
Come to prom with me.
我知道拍电影这事
I know the whole movie situation
对你来说并不容易
was really difficult for you...
我总觉得这是我的错
...and I kind of feel like it was my fault.
所以 我只是想
So I just kind of wanted to
对你做点补偿
make it up to you a little bit.
你是可怜我才约我吗?
Is this a pity date?
不是
No.
我不是因为可怜你才约你
No, it's not a pity date.
Greg 和我一起去舞会吧
Greg, just come to prom with me.
我们一起会很好玩的
I think we'd have a good time.
跟你说了你会找到舞伴的吧
Told you you would get a date.
是
Yep.
西装什么的你就别谢我啦
So you're welcome. For the tux and everything.
谢谢了 妈
Thanks, Mom.
对于你大学的事情 我很生气
I'm very upset about this college thing.
但是你爸说可以等一等
But your father and I can wait
你准备好了我们再谈
till you're ready to talk about it.
谢谢
I appreciate that.
别忘了带女生的胸花
Don't forget your corsage.
好
All right.
我的帅儿子
My handsome boy...
要去舞会啦
...going to prom.
多拍几张照片 好吗?
Take lots of pictures, okay?
Halket街302号
什么?
What's that?
我说 Halket街302号
I said 302 Halket Street.
哈?
Huh?
Halket街302号
Halket街? 好吧 - 好
Halket? Okay. Okay.
知道了
You got it, baby.
你很喜欢这女孩吗?
So you love this girl?
呃 没有 还没到那一步
Uh, no. I wouldn't go that far.
什么?
What?
我- 没有啦
No. I... No.
这样 那你们会在我
Yeah, so you guys are gonna be getting busy
新换的托斯卡纳皮座上亲热吗?
on my brand new Tuscan leather?
- 不 我觉得 - 啥?
No. I think... Huh?
不 我们不会的
No, we're not. I don't think so.
没有啦 我只是逗你玩
Nah, I'm just playing with you.
但是我希望你有这个机会哟
But I do hope you get some.
嗯 一切都听她的
It's really gonna depend on what she wants to do.
如果你真心喜欢她的话
If you really love her, though,
那肯定有机会的
you definitely got a shot.
因为她会知道的
Because she'll know.
她挺好的吧?
She is fine though?
是吗?
Huh?
失败的友谊：第209天
嘿
Hey.
我知道 我帅极了
I know, I look amazing.
我能给你戴上花吗?
Can I put some flowers on you?
这样
Like that.
好的
Okay.
我们看这部片子之前
Before we watch this...
我想道歉 我花了太久了
...I'm sorry it took so long to make.
但是 是因为
But the reason is...
我只是想拍一部不烂的电影
...just couldn't figure out how to get it to not suck.
但是 到头来 我也没找到合适的方式
But... we never really did figure it out.
这片依旧很烂
It still sucks.
我不是真的想跟你说这些
It's not exactly what I wanted to say to you.
但是...
But...
...爱谁谁吧
...whatever.
我们还是先看片吧
Let's just watch this first, okay?
我该叫护士来吗?
Hey, should I get a nurse?
Denise! Denise!
那是我最后一次见到Rachel
That was the last time I saw Rachel.
不久后 她昏迷了
She went into a coma shortly after that,
大概过了十个小时 她就死了
and died about 10 hours later.
我知道 我说过了她没有死
I know I told you she doesn't die.
很抱歉
And I'm sorry.
在我心里
Deep down...
我总觉得 她没有死
...somehow, I didn't think she would.
但是 她死了
But she did.
这是其他部分之后的最后尾声
亲爱的Greg 我听说了
Dear Greg, I heard what happened
在学校的事
with your class work.
还有你大学的事
And with Pitt State.
所以 我给他们写了一封信
So, I wrote them a letter,
想说服他们重新录取你
trying to convince them to let you back in.
如果你想读的话 这里有副本
There's a copy in here, if you want to read it.
真希望能管用 因为这说明
Hopefully, it works, because that would mean...
在坟墓下的我 有可以帮助你的灵力
...I have powers from beyond the grave.
但我觉得你也应该给他们写封信
But you should probably send them something too.
再见了 Greg 你是个好朋友
Goodbye, Greg. You're a good friend.
不过你如果不去上大学的话
Although if you don't go to college,
你还是个傻瓜
you're also an idiot.
不过这个你已经知道了
But you already knew that.
爱你的 Rachel
Love, Rachel.
又及 我还想送你几个我的枕头
I'd also like for you to take some of my pillows.
它们可能会想找个好人家 找到一个被爱的地方
They'll want a good home where they'll be loved.
又又及 不是因为你想的那个原因哦
Not in the way you're thinking,
那太恶心了
that's disgusting.
敬爱的匹茨堡州立大学招生部
Dear Pittsburgh State Admissions:
我代表这么个人 给你们写信
I'm writing on behalf of someone
他用自己生命中一年半的时间
who gave me half a year of his life...
在我最难以陪伴的时候
...at the time when I was at
一直陪着我
my most difficult to be around.
他对自己非常不自信
He has a very low opinion of himself,
所以我认为 你们能收到一个
which is why I think it's necessary...
能看到的真实的他的人的来信
...that you hear from someone
很有必要:
who sees him as he actually is:
他是个无限善良 贴心 甘于奉献
A limitlessly kind, sweet, giving,
并且真诚的人
and genuine person.
无论他自己怎么否认 都不能改变这一点
No matter how much he would deny it.
这一学年 他的成绩滑落
The drop in his academic performance this year...
主要是因为 这段时间
...is the consequence of all the time
他一直在试着让我开心
...and the time he spent making things for me...
而且这段时间让他很难过
...and how hard that was for him.
你可以向他求证
You can ask him about it...
但是他的自我厌恶
...but his sort of over-the-top humility
可能又要出来作怪了
will probably get in the way.
从没人能像他那样让我开心
No one has done more to make me smile than he has.
也再没有人能像他那样
And no one ever could.
Rachel的骨灰被抛洒在
Rachel's ashes were scattered
她家后面的一个公园里
in a park behind her house.
很显然 她曾离家出走过一次
Apparently, she ran away from home once
就想在那儿住来着
and tried to live there.
这个故事是她的姨姨在葬礼上讲的
It was this story her aunt told at the funeral.
她当时想成为一只松鼠
She was trying to become a squirrel.
所以她觉得 如果住在树林里
She thought she could turn into one
一直想着自己能变松鼠
just by being in the forest...
就真能变成松鼠
...and wanting it really bad.
我猜 这就是McCarthy先生所说的
I guess maybe that's what Mr. McCarthy meant...
一个人的一生 会不断地在你面前展开
...about someone's life continuing to unfold.
其实在Rachel死后 再听到她的新鲜事
It was weird to be learning something new
这感觉挺怪的
about Rachel after she died.
但是不知怎么 也让我感觉安心
But somehow, it was reassuring as well.
匹茨堡州立大学 新生录取部
警告：上一个看到这部电影的人 立刻陷入昏迷 并死亡了！